<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-14T20:10:16-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello (Octopress) World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/02/25/hello-octopress-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T18:17:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/02/25/hello-octopress-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my effort to constantly be changing my site, it&rsquo;s now using <a href="http://octopress.org" title="Octopress site">Octopress</a>. Thanks to <a href="http://olivercardoza.com" title="Oliver Cardoza's site">Oliver Cardoza</a> for the tip!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Kiss Kiss Bang Bang [2005]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/08/vsromophas-kiss-kiss-bang-bang/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-08T18:32:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/08/vsromophas-kiss-kiss-bang-bang</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Kiss Kiss Bang Bang is a 2005 crime/dark comedy film, which engages many conventions of the classic film noir genre in a tongue-in-cheek fashion. It is based, in part, on the novel Bodies Are Where You Find Them by Brett Halliday. The cast includes Robert Downey, Jr., Val Kilmer and Michelle Monaghan. The screenplay was written by Shane Black who also directed the film. It was produced by Joel Silver, and co-produced by Downey&rsquo;s wife Susan Downey (who is credited as Susan Levin). The film&rsquo;s title is a reference to Pauline Kael&rsquo;s 1968 book, which in turn was named after a translation of an Italian poster of a James Bond movie, which she called &#8220;perhaps the briefest statement imaginable of the basic appeal of the movies.&rdquo;&ldquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiss_kiss_bang_bang">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kiss_kiss_bang_bang</a></p>

<p>There is a now a new rule for all future films: Robert Downey, Jr. must be the narrator for all of them. Makes for a dark yet very enjoyable time.</p>

<p>8/10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: 9 [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/04/vsromophas-9/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-04T21:10:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/04/vsromophas-9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[Wikipedia is down at the moment, so I can&rsquo;t plagiarize a description from it]</p>

<p>Animated, but don&rsquo;t mistake this for a kid&rsquo;s movie. A new take on a post-apocalyptic world makes for a fun 90 minutes.</p>

<p>9/10 (Just because deus ex machina is used a wee bit too often, mostly courtesy of 7.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Platoon [1986]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/06/17/vsromophas-platoon/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-17T14:48:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/06/17/vsromophas-platoon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Platoon is a 1986 war film written and directed by Oliver Stone and starring Tom Berenger, Willem Dafoe, and Charlie Sheen. It is the first of Stone&rsquo;s Vietnam War trilogy, followed by 1989&rsquo;s Born on the Fourth of July and 1993&rsquo;s Heaven &amp; Earth. Stone wrote the story based upon his experiences as a U.S. infantryman in Vietnam, as a counter to the vision of the war portrayed in John Wayne&rsquo;s The Green Berets.[1] The film won the Academy Award for Best Picture of 1986. In 2007, the American Film Institute placed Platoon at #83 in their &#8220;AFI&rsquo;s 100 Years&hellip; 100 Movies&rdquo; poll. British television channel Channel 4 voted Platoon as the 6th greatest war film ever made, behind Full Metal Jacket and ahead of A Bridge Too Far.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platoon_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Platoon_</a>(film)</p>

<p>There&rsquo;s a reason why people think it&rsquo;s good &ndash; because it is. Does an excellent job of portraying the descent into madness that many involved in the Vietnam War experienced in the face of a faceless enemy.</p>

<p>9.5/10 &ndash; Good. Damned good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Armageddon [1998]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/06/03/vsromophas-armageddon/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-03T15:43:39-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/06/03/vsromophas-armageddon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Armageddon is a 1998 American disaster/science fiction-action film directed by Michael Bay, produced by Jerry Bruckheimer, and released on Disney&rsquo;s Touchstone Pictures label. The movie tells of a group of blue-collar deep-core drillers sent by NASA to stop an asteroid on a collision course with Earth. It featured an all-star cast including Bruce Willis, Ben Affleck, Billy Bob Thornton, Liv Tyler, Will Patton, Peter Stormare, Michael Clarke Duncan and Steve Buscemi. It is now released on Blu-ray.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armageddon_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Armageddon_</a>(1998_film)</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a Michael Bay film. Explosions and clichés. What else do you want? A painfully long two and a half hours&hellip;</p>

<p>5/10 &ndash; because fancy explosions count for something, I guess&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Photos]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/31/new-photos/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-31T18:06:40-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/31/new-photos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New photos! From Kirstin&rsquo;s graduation from the University of Alberta at the beginning of May, as well as random stuff from Waterloo in May.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Fifth Element [1997]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/29/vsromophas-the-fifth-element/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-29T09:50:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/29/vsromophas-the-fifth-element</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Fifth Element is a 1997 science fiction film directed by Luc Besson, starring Bruce Willis, Gary Oldman, Milla Jovovich, Ian Holm, and Chris Tucker. Mostly set during the twenty-third century, the film&rsquo;s central plot involves the survival of humanity, which becomes the duty of a taxicab driver (and former special forces major) named Korben Dallas (Willis) when a young woman (Jovovich) falls into his taxicab. Upon learning of her significance, Korben must join efforts with the girl and a priest (Holm) to recover four mystical stones which are key to defending Earth from an impending attack of pure evil and destruction.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fifth_Element">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fifth_Element</a></p>

<p>I&rsquo;m just&hellip; not sure. This film is weird, and frankly quite boring. About 2/3 of the way through, I was still waiting for the story to start.</p>

<p>4/10. So boring that I can&rsquo;t even think of a reason why I&rsquo;m giving it 4/10.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Shawshank Redemption [1994]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/22/vsromophas-the-shawshank-redemption/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-22T16:09:33-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/05/22/vsromophas-the-shawshank-redemption</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Shawshank Redemption is a 1994 drama film written and directed by Frank Darabont. It is an adaptation of the Stephen King novella Rita Hayworth and Shawshank Redemption. The film stars Tim Robbins as Andrew &#8220;Andy&rdquo; Dufresne and Morgan Freeman as Ellis Boyd &ldquo;Red&rdquo; Redding. The film portrays Andy, who spends nearly two decades in Shawshank State Prison, a fictional penitentiary in Maine, and his friendship with Red, a fellow inmate. Despite a lukewarm box office reception that was barely enough to cover its budget, the film received favorable reviews from critics, multiple award nominations, and has since enjoyed a remarkable life on cable television, VHS, DVD, and Blu-ray. This revival is reflected in its high placement on various lists of great movies.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shawshank_Redemption">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shawshank_Redemption</a></p>

<p>A new entrant in my personal top 10. Intrigue, drama, humour, and one twisted bastard. Redemption is a dish best served by Morgan Freeman.</p>

<p>9/10 &ndash; because the non-word &ldquo;funner&rdquo; is used once, and the fact that Andy&rsquo;s hair somehow stays the same for 10 years in prison bothered me&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: All About Steve [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/20/vsromophas-all-about-steve/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-20T17:16:18-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/20/vsromophas-all-about-steve</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;All About Steve is a 2009 American comedy film directed by Phil Traill.[3] It is distributed by 20th Century Fox. The title is a pun on the 1950 film All About Eve, also made by 20th Century Fox.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_About_Steve">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_About_Steve</a></p>

<p>Yet another punch-out romantic comedy, this time adding a socially awkward, annoying and creepy female lead to try to distinguish itself from the 9001 other films just like it. Alas, methinks the film doth fail in this regard.</p>

<p>3/10 &ndash; 1 point for each enjoyable line in the film.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Citizen Kane [1941]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/20/vsromophas-citizen-kane/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-20T17:11:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/20/vsromophas-citizen-kane</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Citizen Kane is a 1941 American drama film, directed by and starring Orson Welles. The film is often considered the greatest of all time and is particularly praised for its innovative cinematography, music and narrative structure. Citizen Kane was Welles&#8217; first feature film. The film was nominated for Academy Awards in nine categories; it won an Academy Award for Best Writing (Original Screenplay) by Herman Mankiewicz and Welles. It was released by RKO Pictures.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizen_Kane">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizen_Kane</a></p>

<p>An amazing film about an amazing man. Great writing, great acting, great greatness.</p>

<p>9.5/10, because (like many films from this era) it is a bit slow at times.</p>

<p><em>Rosebud.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Requiem for a Dream [2000]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/18/vsromophas-requiem-for-a-dream-2000/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-18T12:57:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/18/vsromophas-requiem-for-a-dream-2000</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Requiem for a Dream is a 2000 film adaptation of the 1978 novel of the same name. [&hellip;] The film depicts different forms of addiction, leading to the characters’ imprisonment in a dream world of delusion and reckless desperation that is subsequently overtaken and devastated by reality.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requiem_for_a_Dream">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requiem_for_a_Dream</a></p>

<p>A shocking and powerful yet somewhat dramatized look into drug addiction from four distinct points of view. Certainly not a happy movie, this would do a better job of preventing drug use than most other methods, I would imagine&hellip;</p>

<p>8/10, for making me feel all unhappy inside.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie Stubs]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/13/movie-stubs/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-13T15:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/13/movie-stubs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Found a bunch of movie stubs in a drawer in my room. For no reason other than boredom and too much free time, they are (listed by year):</p>

<p><strong>2003:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Elf</li>
<li>Lord of the Rings: Return of the King</li>
<li>The Cat in the Hat</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2004:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Harry Potter and the Prizoner of Azkaban</li>
<li>Garfield</li>
<li>Shrek 2</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2005:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>None&hellip;?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2006:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Babel</li>
<li>The Holiday</li>
<li>The Pink Panther</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2007:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Transformers</li>
<li>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</li>
<li>Blood Diamond</li>
<li>The Golden Compass</li>
<li>Beowulf</li>
<li>Children of Men</li>
<li>Transformers (only movie I have ever seen twice in theaters, afaik)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2008:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Burn After Reading</li>
<li>The X Files: I Want to Believe</li>
<li>Hancock</li>
<li>Eagle Eye</li>
<li>Juno</li>
<li>The Dark Knight</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2009:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Transformers 2</li>
<li>Valkyrie</li>
<li>District 9</li>
<li>Watchmen</li>
</ul>


<p>Yep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bad Drivers]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/03/bad-drivers/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-03T21:21:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/03/bad-drivers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In a sorely misguided attempt to make the world a better place, I&rsquo;ve added a bad drivers database. Here, you can add info about any sort of terrible instances of driving you happen upon (in Yellowknife, I observe these types of events several times a day). In theory, people seeing a description of their car and how much of a moron they are online will help them become a better driver. In reality, this is just another way for me (and others) to take out aggression through the wonderful anonymity that the internet provides. Everybody wins!</p>

<p>I, for one, will be keeping a notepad and pen in my car from now on&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary of a Polyphasic Sleeper, Part I - Der Anfang]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T23:59:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this note is written for nobody in particular. More just a reference.</p>

<p>As several people are aware, I have been sleeping polyphasically recently. For those unaware of the meaning of polyphasic, it simply means that you sleep in installments throughout the day, as opposed to once per 24-hour cycle. For example, there is a polyphasic sleep schedule called the &ldquo;Uberman&rdquo; schedule, wherein the individual takes six 20-minute naps in a 24-hour period. Yup, two hours of sleep every 24 hours. I am not an &ldquo;Uber man&rdquo;, though, so I opted for a simpler one.</p>

<p>Basically, I wake up about the same time every morning, about 7:30. Yes, even weekends, and that is key. My classes end around 12:00 usually, so I come home for lunch, and take a half-hour nap (usually 12:30-1:00). I go to afternoon classes, which go to 4:30, come home, and take another half-hour nap from 5:00-5:30 or so. Finally, I sleep again from about 10:30-11:00.</p>

<p>These three half-hour naps are complemented by a big 3 to 5 hour sleep ending at around 7:30am. The length of this nap is variable, and depends on how tired I am any particular day. For example, I sometimes miss a nap in the day for one reason or another. If this is the case, I usually end up being tired at around 2am, and so go to sleep at this point. If I had three excellent naps during the day (as I did today), I&rsquo;ll stay awake until 4 or so. No matter how awake I am, though, this big sleep needs to be at least 3 hours.</p>

<p>To be able to do this, you basically have to trick yourself into going into REM sleep almost instantly, eliminating all the tossing and turning that most people don&rsquo;t realize they do. Meditation helps, looking at the clock worrying that you won&rsquo;t get to sleep does not. I&rsquo;ve only been doing this for a week, and I&rsquo;m already getting into the swing of it. Not only do I fall asleep within a few minutes, but my body and mind are starting to feel tired right around whenever I usually take naps (this is why I don&rsquo;t like skipping naps). I return to my point of waking up at 7:30 on weekends, which is because if you get out of schedule, you may have problems getting back into it.</p>

<p>Some people (my mother) have expressed concerns that this is not healthy. Although I am fairly certain that doing this for extended periods of time would have adverse effects, I will only be doing this until December, and do not believe that it will cause problems. My only complaint is that my legs occasionally hurt due to lack of rest, but this is a problem I have always had, and most people will probably not experience this.</p>

<p>The advantages of this sleep schedule are very apparent, and quite worth it so far. I have about 3 or 4 more hours of being awake every day, which is great. However, the biggest change I have noticed is that when I am awake, I am truly awake. I can work on programming assignments at 2:30 in the morning, and realize the next morning that I actually did them right. This, to me, is the greatest advantage. When sleeping monophasically (one big sleep every night), I would come home after lectures and be exhausted. After sitting around for a couple hours, I could get 2, maybe 3 hours of solid work done in the evening. But after this, I was again too tired to continue. Not anymore. I get about 6 to 8 hours of solid working time per day now, which is great. I can do groceries at 2am (yay 24h Sobey&rsquo;s!) and not mistake Head and Shoulders for crackers. For the first time since arriving at Waterloo, I am almost on time with my assignments!</p>

<p>Hard sleep, hard&hellip; awakedness? I guess that&rsquo;s what this comes down to. Once you&rsquo;re into it, you sleep deeply, even during naps, and you are very awake when you are awake.</p>

<p>3:13am, and I can still type this. See how this works?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best of Interwebz]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/best-of-interwebz/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T18:11:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/best-of-interwebz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Originally published March 13th, 2009)</p>

<p>Stuff I randomly found, through stumble or otherwise. None are videos, some link directly to images, though. Safe for work! Except for the stuff that is not safe for work.</p>

<h3>Humour (may be NSFW):</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://safenow.org/">Safety stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.onelinerz.net/top-100-funny-one-liners/">One-liners</a>
<a href="" title="http://villageofjoy.com/25-motivational-posters/">Motivationals</a>
<a href="" title="http://static.funnyjunk.com/pictures/hipocrit0.jpg">Hypocrisy, thy name is the USA.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.bouldertherapist.com/html/humor/WordPlays/lexophiles.htm">Lexophiles.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.sloshspot.com/blog/08-18-2009/Demetri-Martin-Motivational-Posters-201">Demitri Martin stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.allowe.com/Humor/book/When%20Insults%20Had%20Class.htm">Classy insults</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wegame.com/view/Left4Dead_Playground_Style/sizes/">L4D playground</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.cs.northwestern.edu/~riesbeck/mathphyseng.html">Math/Phys/Eng jokes</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wilk4.com/humor/humorm125.htm">Rodney Dangerfield</a>
<a href="" title="http://venganza.org/jellyfish.html">Jellyfish basically suck.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.zoitz.com/comics/coffee3.png">LOL IT&rsquo;S TRUE</a> (ohsnap.)
<a href="" title="http://www.allowe.com/Humor/computerenhancers.htm">&ldquo;computer enhancers&rdquo;</a></p>

<h3>Photography:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://content1.docstoc.com/flash/National%20Geographic%20Pictures.swf">Ooh, pretty.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.petapixel.com/2009/07/10/7-steps-to-taking-clone-photographs/">Clones, you say?</a>
<a href="" title="http://haha.nu/creative/creative-photos-by-chema-madoz/">Creative &lsquo;n stuff.</a>
<a href="" title="http://gigapica.geenstijl.nl/2009/05/mooi_milieu.html">More pictures</a>
<a href="" title="http://sergeydolya.livejournal.com/">Moskva?</a> (In Russian, but the links below most pictures lead to more pictures. Good pictures. And possibly porn, I haven&rsquo;t checked all the links.)</p>

<h3>Inspirational/BAWWWWW:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://www.catsprn.com/rich-poor.htm">Rich/poor</a>
<a href="" title="http://static.funnyjunk.com/pictures/hipocrit0.jpg">And again.</a> (it&rsquo;s both funny and inspirational, stfu)
<a href="" title="http://imgfave.com/image_cache/124146953043433.jpeg">D&#8217;AWWWWW</a>
<a href="" title="http://rescomp.stanford.edu/~cheshire/EinsteinQuotes.html">Einstein quotes</a></p>

<h3>Howto/Self-improvement</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://www.petapixel.com/2009/07/10/7-steps-to-taking-clone-photographs/">More clones?</a> (again, it&rsquo;s both)
<a href="" title="http://media.npr.org/programs/atc/features/2008/may/foldingchart540.jpg">How to fold things.</a>
<a href="" title="http://thenonconsumeradvocate.com/exceptions-to-katys-compact-buy-nothing-new/">How to not buy things.</a>
<a href="" title="http://mnmlist.com/">How to not anything.</a>
<a href="" title="http://filesharefreak.com/tutorials/how-to-speed-up-torrents-with-low-seeders/">Torrent stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wikihow.com/Make-a-Simple-Beverage-Can-Stove">Beverage can stove, you say?</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.mindcafe.org/9-brain-habits-you-did-not-realize-you-had">Brain habits</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.seql.org/100ways.cfm">100 ways to save the earth (oblig. Al Gore)</a></p>

<h3>Stuff that is interesting for reasons other than above:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://blogs.denverpost.com/captured/2009/09/10/ian-fisher-american-soldier/">Who is fighting the US&rsquo;s war, you ask? This guy!</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.jlc.net/~useless/telsongs.html">Telephone songs</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.worldwithoutus.com/did_you_know.html">Tha future</a> (dunno about anybody else, but makes me feel insignificant&hellip;)
<a href="" title="http://www.prefixmag.com/news/seven-crimes-that-will-get-you-a-smaller-fine-than/32033/">Murder is not all that bad after all.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.toptenz.net/top-10-historical-travel-destinations.php">Travel destinations!</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.nikon.com/about/feelnikon/universcale/index_f.htm">Sizes of things, in comparison to other things.</a> (WARNING: Heavy flash and sound, so turn those speakers off if you&rsquo;re at work!)
<a href="" title="http://content.ytmnd.com/content/a/0/8/a0812774c98903448246c7e213bc1fea.gif">Moar future.</a></p>

<p>These are in no particular order. Browse at thy will.</p>

<p>And for good measure, one YouTube video with arguably the best Rube Goldberg machine ever: <a href="" title="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qybUFnY7Y8w">OK Go &ndash; This Too Shall Pass</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary of a Polyphasic Sleeper, Part II - Der Untergang/Das Ende]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T18:03:37-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Originally published December 5th, 2009)</p>

<p>Follow-up to the previous note about polyphasic sleeping. I have now finished my experiment in polyphasic sleep, and am ready to make some conclusions.</p>

<p>As a recap, my schedule consisted of sleeping about 4 hours a night, with 3 half-hour naps during the day (noon, 5pm and 10pm). I did this for six weeks, with few exceptions. I stayed as close to this schedule as possible, only missing maybe 1 out of every 10 or 15 naps (not bad considering how random and hectic life can be).</p>

<p>One weekend, I did not have any naps, as I spent it in Guelph. Fortunately, I had a good sleep on the Saturday night. However, I was still wrecked for several days afterwards. Even though at that point I had only been doing this for two weeks or so, I was already dependent on my naps &ndash; a testament to the creature of habit that humans really are. Aside from this, I would once in a while miss a nap (usually my 5pm one), which made me a bit tired in the evening, but this was generally remedied by having a slightly longer nap at 10pm.</p>

<p>I also have noted that I became quite good at training myself to wake up without an alarm. Although I always set one as a backup, during my half-hour naps I would generally wake up one or two minutes before it went off. This was not the case in the morning after sleeping 4 hours, though.</p>

<h3>Der Untergang</h3>

<p>In the last week, since exams are coming up, and assignments are no longer a concern, I decided that I would stop the polyphasic sleep. However, being as I am, I decided to do a quick few experiments before I stopped. One of these includes skipping my first two naps. This was, quite simply, disastrous. I was extremely tired in the afternoon and evening, and my 10pm nap ended up being three hours (meaning I was sleeping for two hours while my clock radio was playing before I woke up &ndash; that&rsquo;s how tired I was).</p>

<p>Not really important, but somewhat amusing is that (as I mentioned above) I became so used to sleeping in half-hour chunks that last Saturday I woke up at 8:15am (about normal), but decided to try to sleep in. However, after falling back asleep, I awoke again at 8:45. Tried again, woke up at 9:15. Decided that my body would win this time, got out of bed, and started my day.</p>

<p>Today is going to be my first day that I am not going to take a nap in nearly a month. I am quite tired right now, even though it is not even six o&#8217;clock and I woke up at 10 this morning. Unfortunately, this means that I will not have a very effective evening of studying, as I am finding it extremely hard to focus. Hopefully after a good night&rsquo;s sleep tonight, tomorrow will be more conducive towards studying.</p>

<h3>Das Ende</h3>

<p>Being the scientific (well, Engineering) mind that I am, I did this not only as a way to increase available time, but as a sort of experiment. Some conclusions:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>This did not make me any more difficult to understand/any less coherent. Usually when someone is exhausted, they tend to make less sense. However, I did not receive any comments from people around me that seemed to indicate that this was the case. To me, this indicates that I was probably as confusing as ever, but not in way that indicated exhaustion.</p></li>
<li><p>A big part of the &ldquo;available time&rdquo; part for me was time for assignments and schoolwork. Although I did not notice an increase in my marks in assignments and quizzes since doing this, they certainly did not drop. As is normal with any course, the later material tends to be more difficult to grasp, and my marks generally show this. However, they did not go down by any notable amount. Because I had so much time, I was able to do many of the suggested questions on assignments, read the textbook, and just generally have a better idea of what was going on in my courses.</p></li>
<li><p>As a final note, I had a lot more time to do stuff I wanted to do. In the first half of the term, I was extremely concerned that I would not have enough time to just finish assignments, so I went to few social events, and very little time for anything other than work. Since then, however, I have been to all sorts of EngSoc events, social events, extracurricular stuff, as well as having lots of time to watch movies. LOTS of movies. One might say that thanks to polyphasic sleep, I am far more cultured that I was two months ago, having watched many classic films when I would generally have been sleeping.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If there are mistakes in here, this is most likely because, for the first time six weeks, I am tired. Must&hellip; resist&hellip; urge to nap. Maybe I&rsquo;ll go for groceries, and not at 1:30am this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
