<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T17:12:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beginner PC Builder's Guide]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/03/20/beginner-pc-builders-guide/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T16:50:30-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/03/20/beginner-pc-builders-guide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing this as a guide for a first-time PC builder. Usually these guides are just lists of parts to put together, but I&rsquo;m going to try to make this one more detailed and descriptive. Parts listed here go for about $800 on <a href="http://www.newegg.ca/" title="Newegg.ca">Newegg.ca</a>. For each of these items, go to the Newegg page and click the Specifications tab; that&rsquo;s where the specs I&rsquo;m describing are listed.</p>

<p>Some terms before we get started.</p>

<ul>
<li>A CPU (Central Processing Unit) is the computer&rsquo;s brain. Faster CPU means faster computer, in general usage.</li>
<li>A GPU (Graphics Processing Unit) is the graphics card. Better GPU means better gaming performance.</li>
<li>RAM (Random Access Memory) is memory as people know it. The more memory you have, the more you can run at a time without experiencing slowdowns.</li>
</ul>


<p>These acronyms will be used liberally in this article, so be prepared!</p>

<p>In addition, a request before we get started. If you&rsquo;re a person that is knowledgeable in this area (the term &ldquo;neckbeard&rdquo; comes to mind), please understand that I tried to make this as simple as possible. This means there are some pretty big oversimplifications and generalizations. You can argue with me that CAS latency is critical to get the best performance out of your RAM with me all day, but the fact is that a beginner won&rsquo;t give a shit. So before yelling at me, remember that.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16811139018">Corsair Carbide Series 200R Black Steel / Plastic compact ATX Mid Tower Case</a></h3>

<p><strong>Model</strong><br/>
&ndash; This section is pretty self-explanatory. Just names and stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Type &ndash; ATX Mid Tower: ATX refers (loosely) to the type of motherboard that can be mounted in this case. A majority of them are ATX; other form factors exist, but are much less common. Mid Tower refers mostly to the physical size of the case, which will generally be related to the number of internal bays and space and such. Most &ldquo;typical&rdquo; cases are Mid Tower.
&ndash; Color &ndash; Black: It means it&rsquo;s black. Exciting.
&ndash; Case Material &ndash; Steel structure with molded ABS plastic accent pieces: Most cases are exactly this. Steel for the structure, and plastic for accents and sometimes the internal mounting hardware.
&ndash; With Power Supply &ndash; No: Some cases come sold with a power supply. In general, it&rsquo;s cheaper to buy them this way, but be warned that the power supplies in these sorts of configurations are generally not of particularly high quality.
&ndash; Power Supply Mounted -Bottom: Refers to where in the case the power supply is mounted. More &ldquo;enthusiast&rdquo; cases typically do bottom, as this means the heat from your GPUs and CPU aren&rsquo;t exhausting through the power supply, which can reduce the life of the power supply.
&ndash; Motherboard Compatibility &ndash; Micro ATX / ATX: Related to &ldquo;Type&rdquo;. Micro ATX has the same mounting pattern (screw holes), but smaller boards, as ATX.
&ndash; With Side Panel Window &ndash; No: If you want to be able to look at all the pretty internals, a side window is a good idea!</p>

<p><strong>Expansion</strong><br/>
&ndash; External 5.25&#8221; Drive Bays &ndash; 3: These are where CD/DVD/BR drives are mounted. Also sometimes used for fan controllers, or other front-panel accessories.
&ndash; External 3.5&#8221; Drive Bays &ndash; No: Generally used for floppy drives. Not so common anymore (for obvious reasons).
&ndash; Internal 3.5&#8221; Drive Bays &ndash; 4: Mostly used for mounting hard drives. The more of these, the more storage space you can install.
&ndash; Internal 2.5&#8221; Drive Bays &ndash; 4: Mostly used for mounting solid state drives. Faster storage, yay!
&ndash; Expansion Slots &ndash; 7: These are the slots on the back of the case, where your GPU, discrete sound card, and other expansion cards&#8217; ports will be accessible from the outside of the case. Most mid tower ATX cases have 7.</p>

<p><strong>Front Ports</strong><br/>
&ndash; Front Ports &ndash; 2 x USB 3.0, Audio: Pretty obvious. These are the ports on the front side of the case, for easy access. A lot of cases now have USB 3.0 and audio connections for headphones/mic.</p>

<p><strong>Cooling System</strong><br/>
&ndash; Side Air duct &ndash; No: Some cases have an air duct on the side panel (the one that opens) that is intended to improve cooling.</p>

<p><strong>Physical Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Dimensions &ndash; 16.9&#8221; x 8.3&#8221; x 19.6&#8221;: 43 x 21 x 50 cm, for those of us who use a logical measurement system!</p>

<p><strong>Features</strong>
&ndash; Not going into detail on these. These vary greatly from case to case. Some highlights of this one include tool-free design (meaning you wouldn&rsquo;t need a screwdriver for a lot of the building process) and cabling management systems, which make routing the various cables an easier process.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16817371071">Antec TruePower Classic series TP-550C 550W 80 PLUS GOLD Certified Power Supply</a></h3>

<p><strong>Model</strong><br/>
Again, self-explanatory stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Maximum Power &ndash; 550W: Represents the maximum amount of power this can supply. 500-600W is plenty for most &ldquo;typical&rdquo; systems; if you&rsquo;re planning on having multiple GPUs, might want to look into higher-power ones.
&ndash; Efficiency &ndash; Up to 92%: See next point.
&ndash; Energy-Efficient &ndash; 80 PLUS GOLD Certified: 80 PLUS certifications refer to (simply put) how efficient the power supply is. Greater efficiency means less power lost as heat; in general, there&rsquo;s no reason not to go for a Gold or above certification. They&rsquo;re a bit more expensive, but not by much.
&ndash; Approvals &ndash; UL, cUL, FCC, TUV, CE, CB, CCC, C-Tick, BSMI, Gost-R, SABS: A bunch of acronyms letting you know it won&rsquo;t set your house on fire.
&ndash; Dimensions &ndash; 3.4&#8221;(H) x 5.9&#8221;(W) x 5.5&#8221;(D): The width and height of a power supply are standards, but length can vary. Just make sure there&rsquo;s enough space in your case for it (although this typically isn&rsquo;t a problem).
&ndash; Weight &ndash; 4.6 lbs.: 2.1kg</p>

<p><strong>Features</strong><br/>
&ndash; Again, not going to go into these. Power supplies are even less exciting than cases in this regard. (This particular one brags about its capacitors. How enthralling.)</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16813128519">GIGABYTE GA-970A-UD3 AM3+ AMD 970 + SB950 SATA 6Gb/s USB 3.0 ATX AMD Motherboard</a></h3>

<p><em>Finally, getting into the interesting stuff!</em></p>

<p><strong>Supported CPU</strong><br/>
&ndash; CPU Socket Type &ndash; AM3+: The socket type is the physical arrangements of pins on the CPU. The socket of the CPU you buy and this must match, otherwise they won&rsquo;t work together.
&ndash; CPU Type &ndash; FX / Phenom II / Athlon II / Sempron 100 Series: List of (series of) CPUs that are officially supported. Others (with the correct socket) may work that aren&rsquo;t on this list, but typically it&rsquo;s a good idea to stick with what&rsquo;s here.
&ndash; FSB &ndash; 2400MHz Hyper Transport (4800 MT/s): Ehhh&hellip; not gonna explain this. Not overly important. (Well, it is, extremely, but not to most buyers.)</p>

<p><strong>Chipsets</strong><br/>
&ndash; Chipset &ndash; AMD 970 + SB950: Ehhhhhhh&hellip; same. Not particularly interesting or important to most buyers.</p>

<p><strong>Memory</strong><br/>
&ndash; Number of Memory Slots &ndash; 4×240pin: Refers to the number (and type) of RAM slots on the motherboard. More slots means more memory, but 4 is a just fine number.
&ndash; Memory Standard &ndash; DDR3 2000(O.C.) / 1866 / 1600 / 1333 / 1066: RAM speed. RAM can run at several speeds; as long as there is some overlap between the RAM you buy and this spec, you&rsquo;ll be a-okay.
&ndash; Maximum Memory Supported &ndash; 32GB: Self-explanatory. Not many people require 32GB of RAM, so that&rsquo;s a fine limit.
&ndash; Channel Supported &ndash; Dual Channel: Most RAM is sold in Dual-Channel kits. Pages could be written on the performance implications of this, but the easy answer is use a dual-channel kit with a dual-channel motherboard.</p>

<p><strong>Expansion Slots</strong><br/>
<em>This is where GPUs, soundcards, and expansion cards get plugged in.</em>
&ndash; PCI Express 2.0 x16 &ndash; 2 (x16, x4): Generally used for GPUs. PCI Express 3.0 does exist, and a lot of GPUs support it, but using a 3.0 card with 2.0 will be absolutely fine (since the 2.0 spec is plenty fast enough anyway). The x16 and x4 refer to operating speeds &ndash; as long as x16 is there, you&rsquo;re good for running the latest GPUs.
&ndash; PCI Express x1 &ndash; 3: Typically used for sound cards, USB 3.0 expansion cards, or eSATA expansion cards
&ndash; PCI Slots &ndash; 2: Legacy slots. Not really used by much anymore, unless you&rsquo;ve got old stuff you need to interface with.</p>

<p><strong>Storage Devices</strong><br/>
&ndash; SATA 6Gb/s &ndash; 6 x SATA 6Gb/s: Used by hard drives, solid state drives, and CD/DVD/BR drives. 6Gb/s refers to the maximum transfer speed, and is the current norm.
&ndash; SATA RAID &ndash; 0/1/5/10/JBOD: Most people don&rsquo;t RAID, so ignore this. However, fun trivia &ndash; JBOD stands for &ldquo;Just a Bunch Of Disks&rdquo;. (Seriously.)</p>

<p><strong>Onboard Video</strong><br/>
&ndash; Onboard Video Chipset &ndash; None: If you&rsquo;re buying a GPU, &ldquo;None&rdquo; is absolutely fine, as the GPU replaces this. If you aren&rsquo;t buying a GPU&hellip; buy a GPU.</p>

<p><strong>Onboard Audio</strong><br/>
&ndash; Describes the built-in audio card. Generally they&rsquo;re all the same, and are decent.</p>

<p><strong>Onboard LAN</strong><br/>
&ndash; Describes the built-in ethernet card. Same as above; most are up to gigabit (1000Mbps) now, which is a hell of a lot faster than your internet connection anyway.</p>

<p><strong>Rear Panel Ports</strong><br/>
&ndash; Port list. These are where you plug stuff in. Most motherboards have approximately the same ones. On new motherboards, make sure to get one with at least a couple USB 3.0 ports, because why not.</p>

<p><strong>Internal I/O Connectors</strong><br/>
&ndash; These refer to the ports on the motherboard that aren&rsquo;t accessible from the outside of the case. Big thing to look for here is the USB 3.0 and front panel audio connectors if your case has these connectors on the front (this is where you plug them in).</p>

<p><strong>Physical Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Form Factor &ndash; ATX: Already explained, mostly.
&ndash; Dimensions &ndash; 12.0&#8221; x 9.6&#8221;: Obvious.
&ndash; Power Pin &ndash; 24 Pin: Back in the day, some were 20 Pin. &ldquo;Back in the day&rdquo; being like&hellip; 1998.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16819113291">AMD FX-4130 Zambezi 3.8GHz Socket AM3+ Quad-Core Desktop Processor FD4130FRGUBOX</a></h3>

<p><strong>Model</strong><br/>
&ndash; Brand &ndash; AMD: Really only two, AMD and Intel. Generally (and I&rsquo;m being very general here) Intel aims for a slightly higher performance (and price) bracket.
&ndash; Series &ndash; FX-Series: This is what should match the CPU Typesection under the motherboard&rsquo;s Supported CPUsection.
&ndash; Model &ndash; FD4130FRGUBOX: Try pronouncing these phonetically for fun.</p>

<p><strong>CPU Socket Type</strong><br/>
&ndash; CPU Socket Type &ndash; Socket AM3+: Needs to match the socket type of your motherboard, otherwise you&rsquo;re going to have a bad day.</p>

<p><strong>Tech Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Core Name &ndash; Zambezi: I think they misspelled Zamboni. Not important except for the hardcore-est of hardware enthusiasts.
&ndash; Multi-Core &ndash; Quad-Core: More cores is better, generally speaking, but more cores is also more expensive, generally speaking. Quad core is pretty much the sweet spot right now in terms of price and performance.
&ndash; Name &ndash; FX-4130: Another fun one to pronounce phonetically. And another one that isn&rsquo;t overly important.
&ndash; Operating Frequency &ndash; 3.8GHz: Higher frequency is faster, but creates more heat. Think of the CPU like a river, and water is the work you want to do &ndash; more cores means a wider river, higher operating frequency means higher current. Both result in more water being moved, just in different ways.
&ndash; L2 Cache &ndash; 4MB: <em>Ignore</em>
&ndash; Manufacturing Tech &ndash; 32nm: <em>All</em>
&ndash; 64-Bit Support &ndash; Yes: <em>Of</em>
&ndash; Hyper-Transport Support &ndash; Yes: <em>These</em>
&ndash; Virtualization Technology Support &ndash; Yes: <em>Things</em></p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820231314">G.SKILL Ripjaws Series 8GB (2 x 4GB) 240-Pin DDR3 SDRAM DDR3 1600 (PC3 12800) Desktop Memory Model F3-12800CL9D-8GBRL</a></h3>

<p><em>I hate how convoluted RAM specs are.</em></p>

<p><strong>Model</strong><br/>
&ndash; Brand &ndash; G.SKILL: Most are somewhat ridiculous.
&ndash; Series &ndash; Ripjaws Series: Most of these are reallyridiculous.
&ndash; Model &ndash; F3-12800CL9D-8GBRL: Oh what the hell.
&ndash; Type &ndash; 240-Pin DDR3 SDRAM: Ah, this is important. This refers to the physical type. This should match the memory requirements of the motherboard (in general, new stuff will all be DDR3 SDRAM, which all has 240 pins).</p>

<p><strong>Tech Spec</strong><br/>
&ndash; Capacity &ndash; 8GB (2 x 4GB): How much RAM you&rsquo;re getting. the 2 x 4GB means it comes in two 4GB modules. Remember that your motherboard has a limited number of slots for modules.
&ndash; Speed &ndash; DDR3 1600 (PC3 12800): As long as this is within the list of memory speeds supported by your motherboard, you&rsquo;ll be good.
&ndash; Cas Latency &ndash; 9: <em>Nobody</em>
&ndash; Timing &ndash; 9-9-9-24-2: <em>Cares</em>
&ndash; Voltage &ndash; 1.5V: <em>About</em>
&ndash; ECC &ndash; No: <em>These</em>
&ndash; Buffered/Registered &ndash; Unbuffered: <em>Specs.</em>
&ndash; Multi-channel Kit &ndash; Dual Channel Kit: Should match the Channel Supported spec of your motherboard. Not strictly required, but I don&rsquo;t want to start a flame war about the relative merits of this.
&ndash; Heat Spreader &ndash; Yes: It&rsquo;s like a radiator for your RAM, because you&rsquo;re that hardcore. (Helps with heat dissipation, most have them.)</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16820147247">SAMSUNG 840 EVO MZ-7TE120BW 2.5&#8221; 120GB SATA III TLC Internal Solid State Drive (SSD)</a></h3>

<p><em>Solid-state drives are more expensive than their mechanical counterparts (hard disk drives, HDDs), but worth the price difference.</em></p>

<p><strong>General</strong><br/>
The usual stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Physical</strong><br/>
&ndash; Form Factor &ndash; 2.5&#8221;: SSDs are typically 2.5&#8221;, whereas hard drives are 3.5&#8221; for desktops. Just make sure your case has enough internal 2.5&#8221; drive bays for the number of drives you want.
&ndash; Capacity &ndash; 120GB: Amount of space. Because SSDs are more expensive, they also come in smaller sizes for their cost. That said, worth the speed tradeoff. Memory Components &ndash; TLC: Ignore.
&ndash; Interface &ndash; SATA III: SATA III = SATA 6 Gbps. Just make sure your motherboard has some connectors for it, which most modern ones will.
&ndash; <em>The rest of the fields in this category can be ignored, or are obvious.</em></p>

<p><strong>Performance</strong><br/>
SSDs are fast. Some are faster, some are slower, and this is where the differences will be shown. Unless you buy a really cheap one, they&rsquo;re all going to be what can only be described as &ldquo;damned fast&rdquo; compared to hard drives.</p>

<p><strong>Environmental</strong><br/>
&ndash; Power Consumption (Idle) &ndash; 0.045W: a.k.a. About 1/150th of a mechanical hard drive.
&ndash; Operating Temperature &ndash; 0°C ~ +60°C: Don&rsquo;t boil it, and don&rsquo;t freeze it.
&ndash; Operating Humidity &ndash; 5% to 95% RH: Also don&rsquo;t use it in the rain.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.newegg.ca/Product/Product.aspx?Item=N82E16814202050">SAPPHIRE 100364L Radeon R9 270X 2GB 256-Bit GDDR5 PCI Express 3.0 x16 HDCP Ready CrossFireX Support Video Card</a></h3>

<p><em>I take it back. GPUs are much, much worse than RAM.</em></p>

<p><strong>Model</strong><br/>
&ndash; Brand &ndash; SAPPHIRE: This is where the terms &ldquo;GPU&rdquo; and &ldquo;graphics card&rdquo; separate. This graphics card is made by Sapphire, whereas the GPU is decribed in the Chipset section below.
&ndash; Model &ndash; 100364L: Obvs.</p>

<p><strong>Interface</strong>
Interface &ndash; PCI Express 3.0 x16: This is the slot it goes into on the motherboard. Don&rsquo;t be too concerned if it&rsquo;s PCI Express 2.0 or 3.0 &ndash; 3.0 is faster, but very few (if any) current cards actually hit the limit of 2.0 anyway.</p>

<p><strong>Chipset</strong><br/>
&ndash; Chipset Manufacturer &ndash; AMD: Same company that makes the CPU!
&ndash; GPU &ndash; Radeon R9 270X: This is the GPU model. There are tonnes of these. When somebody asks what video card you have, this is what you&rsquo;d tell them.
&ndash; Boost Clock &ndash; 1070MHz: Mostly ignore.
&ndash; Stream Processors &ndash; 1280 Stream Processors: So, know how quad-core means a wider river? Try 1280 cores. No, the number of GPU cores is not directly comparable to CPU cores, but more is better here in the same way.</p>

<p><strong>Memory</strong><br/>
&ndash; Effective Memory Clock &ndash; 1400MHz (Effective 5600 Mbps): Faster is better &ndash; this is the speed of the memory on the graphics card itself.
&ndash; Memory Size &ndash; 2GB: Size of the memory on the graphics card itself. This is faster for the GPUs to access than system RAM, so more here means better gaming performance.
&ndash; Memory Interface &ndash; 256-Bit: Ignore.
&ndash; Memory Type &ndash; GDDR5: Ignore. They&rsquo;re all GDDR5 anyway.</p>

<p><strong>3D API</strong><br/>
<em>Everything is DirectX 11.2ish and OpenGL 4.2ish now. Not particularly important.</em></p>

<p><strong>Ports</strong><br/>
<em>Make sure any monitors you want to connect have one of these types of connectors. Typically HDMI is the easiest option.</em></p>

<p><strong>General</strong><br/>
&ndash; Max Resolution: Make sure the card you choose is capable of driving that enormous, high-resolution monitor you bought.
&ndash; Eyefinity Support &ndash; Yes: AMD-specific technology, not overly important for most.
&ndash; CrossFireX Support &ndash; Yes: AMD has CrossFireX and nVidia has SLI; both allow for using multiple cards together. Unless you&rsquo;re a hardcore gamer that can afford two top-end cards&hellip; just don&rsquo;t.
&ndash; Cooler &ndash; With Fan: Most are fan-cooled. Really low-end ones can be passive (just a heatsink), and some are liquid cooled, but these are rare.
&ndash; Slot Width &ndash; Dual Slot: Takes up two Expansion Slots on your case. Also beware that on most motherboards, a dual slot card will block one of the expansion slots (usually one you won&rsquo;t need, but worth being aware of).
&ndash; Operating Systems Supported: Usually Windows. Very few manufacturers make Linux/Mac drivers.
&ndash; System Requirements &ndash; 500W (or greater) power supply with two 75W 6-pin PCI Express power connector recommended: Graphics cards are the biggest power consumer in a typical desktop, so make sure your chosen power supply has enough power to run it.
&ndash; Power Connector &ndash; 2 x 6-Pin: They all are. Well, some aren&rsquo;t. But most are.
&ndash; Dual-Link DVI Supported &ndash; Yes: 2006 called.
&ndash; HDCP Ready &ndash; Yes: 2010 called.
&ndash; Card Dimensions &ndash; 8.98&#8221; x 4.29&#8221; x 1.38&#8221;: Strangely enough, this one can actually be important. Some cards are extremely long and will have a hard time fitting in your case.</p>

<p><strong>Features</strong><br/>
Each card has about a billion features, and half of them are just marketing fluff anyway.</p>

<p><strong>Packaging</strong><br/>
Typically come with some cables to connect it to the power supply and monitor(s).</p>

<p>Holy shit, that&rsquo;s everything. This is a very, very summarized view. I tried to give a brief comment on things that are relevant to beginner/novice PC builder to attempt to make it a bit simpler. But it&rsquo;s still pretty goddamn complicated, so I recommend always getting a friend who has experience in the area to give you a hand!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello (Octopress) World!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/02/25/hello-octopress-world/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T18:17:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2014/02/25/hello-octopress-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my effort to constantly be changing my site, it&rsquo;s now using <a href="http://octopress.org" title="Octopress site">Octopress</a>. Thanks to <a href="http://olivercardoza.com" title="Oliver Cardoza's site">Oliver Cardoza</a> for the tip!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Behind Enemy Lines [2001]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-behind-enemy-lines/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:04:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-behind-enemy-lines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Based on a fictional US Navy F-18 navigator who gets shot down over a supposedly DMZ during what is supposedly the Bosnian conflict of the early &lsquo;90s.</p>

<p>Good enough storyline, somewhat original. Cheesy special effects (it was almost 10 years ago, you know), and too many clichés. Evil Russian sniper anyone?</p>

<p>5.2445/10, for lack of imagination and trying to make me take Owen Wilson seriously.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 2 February 2010 at 19:42</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Starship Troopers [1997]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-starship-troopers/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:03:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-starship-troopers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sci-fi that &ldquo;follows a young soldier named Johnny Rico and his exploits in the Mobile Infantry, a futuristic military unit. Rico&rsquo;s military career progresses from recruit to non-commissioned officer and finally to officer against the backdrop of an interstellar war between mankind and an arachnoid species known as &#8220;the Bugs&rdquo;.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starship_Troopers_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starship_Troopers_</a>(film</p>

<p>Special effects that make some newer films look amateur, this is a surprisingly funny (read: over-the-top and ridiculous) parody of militarism and totalitarianism. Lame storyline and acting, but hey, this is science fiction. Get used to it.</p>

<p>7.56/10</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 3 February 2010 at 19:48</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Fight Club [1999]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-fight-club/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:02:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-fight-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Fight Club is a 1999 American film adapted from the 1996 novel of the same name by Chuck Palahniuk. The film was directed by David Fincher and stars Edward Norton, Brad Pitt, and Helena Bonham Carter. Norton plays the unnamed protagonist, an &#8220;everyman&rdquo; who is discontented with his white-collar job in American society. He forms a &ldquo;fight club&rdquo; with soap salesman Tyler Durden, played by Pitt, and becomes embroiled in a relationship with him and a dissolute woman, Marla Singer, played by Carter.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_Club_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_Club_</a>(film)</p>

<p>An intricate (but not overly confusing) storyline, intense (yet believable) acting, and a kickass soundtrack. Oh, and a sick sense of humour throughout the entire thing. No wonder people love this film. Definitely a new addition to my top ten. Messed up and awesome.</p>

<p>9.9999/10, because nobody is perfect.</p>

<p>(As a not related note, is there a single film Edward Norton is in that ISN&rsquo;T awesome? I mean, seriously&hellip;)</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 4 February 2010 at 20:28</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: (500) Days of Summer [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-500-days-of-summer/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T19:55:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-500-days-of-summer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;(500) Days of Summer is a 2009 romantic-drama-comedy film. It was written by Scott Neustadter and Michael H. Weber, directed by Marc Webb, produced by Mark Waters, and stars Joseph Gordon-Levitt and Zooey Deschanel. The story is presented in a nonlinear narrative structure and depicts a memory-driven look at a failed romance.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/</a>(500)_Days_of_Summer</p>

<p>Not a movie that I would usually like, but I was somehow smiling the whole way through. Then again, that could just be Zooey Deschanel. One of those films that bills itself as &ldquo;quirky&rdquo;, this is one of the few that does it relatively well. Not sure that the comedy tag fits this film &ndash; although amusing, I&rsquo;m not sure that I ever actually laughed. Well, except at the impromptu musical number.</p>

<p>8.5/10 &ndash; would be 7.5, but Zooey Deschanel&rsquo;s cuteness gives an extra point.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 4 February 2010 at 23:58</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Top Gun [1986]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-top-gun/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T19:54:11-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-top-gun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;This film stars Tom Cruise, Kelly McGillis, Anthony Edwards, Val Kilmer, Meg Ryan, and Tom Skerritt. Cruise plays Lieutenant Pete &#8220;Maverick&rdquo; Mitchell, a young Naval aviator on board the aircraft carrier USS Enterprise. He and his Naval Flight Officer (Radar Intercept Officer &ndash; the &ldquo;RIO&rdquo; &ndash; the &ldquo;back seater&rdquo; in the two-man F-14 Tomcat) Lt. j.g. Nick &ldquo;Goose&rdquo; Bradshaw are given the chance to train at the Navy&rsquo;s Fighter Weapons School, after the pilot above him in the squadron rankings resigns from duty following a very stressful mission. This film depicts Maverick&rsquo;s progress through the training, his romance with a female instructor, and his overcoming a crisis of confidence following a fatal training accident.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_gun">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_gun</a></p>

<p>No idea why this film was so popular. Maybe it&rsquo;s just the 80s hairstyles, but sitting through the entire length of this film was actually quite excruciating. Not sure if it&rsquo;s action, romance, or just a blatant US Navy recruiting project.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 5 February 2010 at 20:28</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Boondock Saints [1999]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-the-boondock-saints/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T19:53:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-the-boondock-saints</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Boondock Saints is a 1999 crime thriller film written and directed by Troy Duffy. The film stars Sean Patrick Flanery and Norman Reedus as Catholic Irish American fraternal twins, Conner and Murphy MacManus, who become vigilantes after killing two members of the Russian Mafia in self-defense. After a &#8220;message from God&rdquo;, the brothers, together with their friend David Della Rocco, set out to rid their home city of Boston, Massachusetts of crime and evil; all the while being pursued by Special Agent Paul Smecker (Willem Dafoe).&#8221;</p>

<p>Irish wit. Excessive use of the word &ldquo;fuck&rdquo; (in all senses). Bloody violence. And Willem DaFoe dressed as a woman. What&rsquo;s not to like? Well, not overly great storytelling and a sense that this film has no point is what&rsquo;s not to like.</p>

<p>6/10. Entertaining, but not stellar.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 9 February 2010 at 00:03</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Constantine [2005]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-constantine/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T19:44:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-constantine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Constantine is a 2005 American film based on Vertigo Comics’ Hellblazer comic book, with some plot elements being taken from the “Dangerous Habits” story arc (issues #41–46) and others—such as the inclusion of Papa Midnite—from the Original Sins trade paperback.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constantine_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Constantine_</a>(film)</p>

<p>Keanu Reeves being moody. Shia LeBoeuf being annoying. Nothing to see here folks, move along.</p>

<p>3.9999999999/10 &ndash; Only redeeming feature is Peter Stormare&rsquo;s short part as Lucifer and about 2 amusing lines.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 27 February 2010 at 20:20</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Michael Clayton [2007]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-michael-clayton/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T19:43:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-michael-clayton</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Michael Clayton is a 2007 American dramatic film written and directed by Tony Gilroy and produced by Sydney Pollack. It stars George Clooney, Tom Wilkinson, Tilda Swinton, and Sydney Pollack. It chronicles the attempts of attorney Michael Clayton to cope with a colleague&rsquo;s apparent mental breakdown and the corruption and murderous intrigue of a major client of his law firm being sued in a class action case involving toxic agrochemicals.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Clayton_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Michael_Clayton_</a>(film)</p>

<p>I hate to be clichéd, but this is the only film I have ever seen that I can describe as &ldquo;gripping drama&rdquo;. Damned good, with a hint of oak aftertaste.</p>

<p>8.5262/10 &ndash; Tilda Swindon&rsquo;s fake american accent is annoying at times, and the overload of legal and business terms can be somewhat detrimental to the flow of the story in parts.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 1 March 2010 at 00:57</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: 1984 [1984]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-1984/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T19:42:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-1984</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Nineteen Eighty-Four (sometimes 1984) is a British film, released in 1984, based upon George Orwell&rsquo;s novel of the same name, following the life of Winston Smith in Oceania, a country run by a totalitarian government. The film was directed by Michael Radford and stars John Hurt, Richard Burton (in his last film role) and Suzanna Hamilton.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1984_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1984_</a>(1984_film)</p>

<p>Thought-provoking but at times very hard to follow (I blame 80&rsquo;s recording technology). Whether you like it or not, this one is going (or already has gone) down in history. Not sure if the book is better, as I have not read it.</p>

<p>8.11(repeating decimal)/10.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 22 March 2010 at 23:10</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Requiem for a Dream [2000]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-requiem-for-a-dream/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T19:40:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/08/vsromophas-requiem-for-a-dream</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“Requiem for a Dream is a 2000 film adaptation of the 1978 novel of the same name. [&hellip;] The film depicts different forms of addiction, leading to the characters’ imprisonment in a dream world of delusion and reckless desperation that is subsequently overtaken and devastated by reality.” – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requiem_for_a_Dream">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Requiem_for_a_Dream</a></p>

<p>A shocking and powerful yet somewhat dramatized look into drug addiction from four distinct points of view. Certainly not a happy movie, this would do a better job of preventing drug use than most other methods, I would imagine…</p>

<p>8/10, for making me feel all unhappy inside.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 18 April 2010 at 18:58</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Citizen Kane [1941]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-citizen-kane/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T14:40:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-citizen-kane</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Citizen Kane is a 1941 American drama film, directed by and starring Orson Welles. The film is often considered the greatest of all time and is particularly praised for its innovative cinematography, music and narrative structure. Citizen Kane was Welles&#8217; first feature film. The film was nominated for Academy Awards in nine categories; it won an Academy Award for Best Writing (Original Screenplay) by Herman Mankiewicz and Welles. It was released by RKO Pictures.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizen_Kane">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizen_Kane</a></p>

<p>An amazing film about an amazing man. Great writing, great acting, great greatness.</p>

<p>9.5/10, because (like many films from this era) it is a bit slow at times.</p>

<p>Rosebud.</p>

<p><em>Originally published on Facebook on 20 April 2010 at 02:21</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: All About Steve [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-all-about-steve/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T14:36:36-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-all-about-steve</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>“All About Steve is a 2009 American comedy film directed by Phil Traill.[3] It is distributed by 20th Century Fox. The title is a pun on the 1950 film All About Eve, also made by 20th Century Fox.” – <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_About_Steve">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/All_About_Steve</a></p>

<p>Yet another punch-out romantic comedy, this time adding a socially awkward, annoying and creepy female lead to try to distinguish itself from the 9001 other films just like it. Alas, methinks the film doth fail in this regard.</p>

<p>3/10 – 1 point for each enjoyable line in the film.</p>

<p><em>Originally published to Facebook on 20 April 2010 at 23:16</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Shawshank Redemption [1994]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-the-shawshank-redemption/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-05T14:35:04-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/05/vsromophas-the-shawshank-redemption</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Shawshank Redemption is a 1994 drama film written and directed by Frank Darabont. It is an adaptation of the Stephen King novella Rita Hayworth and Shawshank Redemption. The film stars Tim Robbins as Andrew &#8220;Andy&rdquo; Dufresne and Morgan Freeman as Ellis Boyd &ldquo;Red&rdquo; Redding. The film portrays Andy, who spends nearly two decades in Shawshank State Prison, a fictional penitentiary in Maine, and his friendship with Red, a fellow inmate. Despite a lukewarm box office reception that was barely enough to cover its budget, the film received favorable reviews from critics, multiple award nominations, and has since enjoyed a remarkable life on cable television, VHS, DVD, and Blu-ray. This revival is reflected in its high placement on various lists of great movies.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shawshank_Redemption">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Shawshank_Redemption</a></p>

<p>A new entrant in my personal top 10. Intrigue, drama, humour, and one twisted bastard. Redemption is a dish best served by Morgan Freeman.</p>

<p>9/10 &ndash; because the non-word &ldquo;funner&rdquo; is used once, and the fact that Andy&rsquo;s hair somehow stays the same for 10 years in prison bothered me&hellip;</p>

<p><em>Originally published to Facebook on 22 May 2010 at 22:10</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting PC Headset Mic to Mixer (Steinberg CI1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/10/19/connecting-pc-headset-mic-to-mixer-steinberg-ci1/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-19T18:40:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/10/19/connecting-pc-headset-mic-to-mixer-steinberg-ci1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is what I would thoroughly classify under, &ldquo;rare, but irksome&rdquo; problems.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got a Steinberg CI1 mixer that I use as an input for my guitar, and have my KRK studio monitors plugged into for output. It&rsquo;s plugged into my computer as well, so I can either run the guitar to the monitors, or my PC&rsquo;s sound (or both). The mixer uses either line-level or +48V phantom power for the inputs. Which is great for a guitar, or for a professional microphone, but the microphones in PC headsets (mostly condenser mics, which are fairly cheap) run at the +5V supplied by a computer&rsquo;s soundcard. Which is&hellip; awkward, and since I just bought a shiny new Razer Blackshark headset, I figured I should find a way to plug the PC mic into the mixer, for convenience and whatnot.</p>

<p>So, I found a way. It takes the mic signal from the 3.5mm TRS connector from the headset, amplifies it, and outputs to a &frac14;&#8221; TS connector (although it could just as easily be a 3.5mm TS jack, if that&rsquo;s what you required). Pretty simple, parts list as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>3.5mm female TRS connector jack</li>
<li>&frac14;&#8221; male TS connector (with some cable attached, I just used part of an old guitar cable)</li>
<li>10uF capacitor (I&rsquo;d say 16V+, the one I&rsquo;ve used is 100V, but that&rsquo;s overkill, just what I had)</li>
<li>2.2kOhm resistor</li>
<li>9V battery connector</li>
</ul>


<p>The circuit diagram is as follows:</p>

<p><img src="http://mahler.ca/notablog/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/PC-Headset-to-Mixer-amp.jpg" alt="Circuit diagram for amp" /></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s uhh&hellip; That&rsquo;s pretty much it. I put it into a fancy little project box, to make it fancy, as below. Aside from that, just connect the 9V battery whenever you need to use the mic, plug your headset into the 3.5mm end, then plug the &frac14;&#8221; side into the mixer, and you should be good to go!</p>

<p>Fancy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Psychology? That's the (Easiest|hardest) Degree Ever!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/05/26/psychology-thats-the-easiest-hardest-degree-ever/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-26T19:36:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/05/26/psychology-thats-the-easiest-hardest-degree-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Possible things, then, will be all those things that are not impossible things &ndash; that is, all those things that are either contingent or necessary. If there are no necessary things then all possible things will be contingent and all contingent things will be possible. If there is a necessary thing, however, then there will be a possible thing which is not contingent.&rdquo; &ndash; Philosophy: The Quest For Truth (Pojman, Vaughn)</p>

<p>This is a quote from a textbook for a first year philosophy course.</p>

<p>I have long maintained that the idea that some academic programs are harder than others is preposterous. I&rsquo;ve experienced this from both ends &ndash; people telling me that I &ldquo;must be really smart to be in computer engineering&rdquo;, since there&rsquo;s &ldquo;no way they could do that!&rdquo;, as well as those informing me that psychology is &ldquo;waaaaaay harder&rdquo; than computer engineering, because it requires &ldquo;hours of reading every day, and you&rsquo;ve got to write a thesis and if you don&rsquo;t get published your entire degree is a waste!&rdquo; Both of these statements I find to be a bit&hellip; well, rather silly.</p>

<p>For example: I find the textbook paragraph above extremely difficult to parse and understand, whereas a language-brain-type would have no issue doing so; that said, I am likely able to parse and understand concepts of analog signals better than they would. It&rsquo;s much less a matter of the content, and more a matter of the reader or learner. Different people have difficulty with different things, simple as that.</p>

<p>While anecdotal evidence is a logical fallacy (see <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/anecdotal">https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/anecdotal</a>), and I am in no way basing my conclusions off just this, my own progress and marks (most notably in my university career, although a similar analysis could be done for high school if I had the marks accessible) are a good example of how wrong this claim is. Last term &ndash; my second half of 3rd year computer engineering (honours) at the University of Waterloo &ndash; I took Psych 101 as an elective. You know, THE Psych 101 course. The one that seemingly everybody who has ever been to university has taken &ndash; and passed without any effort. Well, I got a lower mark in THE Psych 101 course than I did in my 3rd-year computer networks course, despite Psych 101 being generally recognized as a bird course for first years. In fact, I received a lower mark in Psych 101 than I received in my 3rd-year engineering economics course as well. Speaking of that, I also took Econ 102 (macroeconomics, another one of those everybody-takes-it first year courses) in the same term, and received nearly the same mark in it as the aforementioned 3rd year engineering economics course &ndash; a course that should, by it&rsquo;s description at least, be much more difficult. So what gives?</p>

<p>Now, you might think this breaks down to amount of effort put in. Undoubtedly, I spent more time on my engineering courses than I did my Psych 101 and Econ 102 electives. But, quite frankly, that wasn&rsquo;t the root cause of the lower marks. The entire term, I knew that it wasn&rsquo;t time, or studying that would enable me to get 100% in these supposedly simple, throwaway courses. I knew what would, though &ndash; nothing. Well, nothing short of a brain transplant. Thing is, I don&rsquo;t have the brain required for social sciences, or economics, or (apparently) philosophy. These are topics that require huge amounts of memorization, which I am simply unable to do (unless you&rsquo;re talking Arrested Development quotes, that&rsquo;s an exception). They also are topics where there is, at times, very little connectedness &ndash; although this may only be from my perspective, really. I find the topics we learn about in our computer engineering courses to be very interrelated, both within topics in a course as well as within courses (even spanning multiple years), whereas I don&rsquo;t see this same sort of network forming with other subjects. Adding to my perhaps skewed perception is the professors teaching these courses. My engineering economics course and Econ 102 had similar content, but the engineering one was framed in such a way that it had more of that connectedness, and I was therefore able to do just fine in it. On the other hand, Econ 102 was presented more as a loosely-connected list of concepts, without much &ldquo;glue&rdquo; tying them together in real-world application, making it much harder for me to really understand what was going on.</p>

<p>So, am I insane? Or do I have a point here? I don&rsquo;t actually know to be honest. Thing is, at this point, having been through most of a university degree, there&rsquo;s really no way for me to compare. If I were to pursue a degree in psychology after graduating, it would be an unfair comparison. I already have experience with the university education system, allowing me to effectively game the system at times, much like students do in high school. (Other students, I mean. Not me. I was a workaholic for those four years. Totally.)</p>

<p>In conclusion (he wrote, feeling a bit like a high school student trapped in an essay), it seems to me that while not all degrees are created equal, not all people are created equal either, and we therefore cannot judge the relative merit of degrees based on perceived difficulty. The grass is always greener on the other side of the fence, so we tend to take pity on ourselves and think that we&rsquo;re in the roughest spot, and that everybody else has it easy. Well guess what? They don&rsquo;t. Stop saying they do. Putting them down to make yourself feel better kinda makes you a jerk, and if there&rsquo;s one thing I know, there isn&rsquo;t a course that is designed for the jerk-brained.</p>

<p>(In preparation for philosophy essay due next week, I am adding a few sentences down here to bring the word count up to 1000 words. It&rsquo;s amazing that I can just braindump this much without even trying, whereas said philosophy essay is taking far, far more effort. Shoot, 989 at that last sentence. So, now I&rsquo;m at 1000. Exactly, actually.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Breakfast Club [1985]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/02/19/vsromophas-the-breakfast-club/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T12:21:16-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/02/19/vsromophas-the-breakfast-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Breakfast Club is a 1985 American coming of age comedy-drama film written and directed by John Hughes and starring Emilio Estevez, Anthony Michael Hall, Judd Nelson, Molly Ringwald, and Ally Sheedy. The storyline follows five teenagers (each a member of a different high school clique) as they spend a Saturday in detention together and come to realize that they are all deeper than their respective stereotypes&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Breakfast_Club">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Breakfast_Club</a></p>

<p>Despite my dislike of all things &lsquo;80s, and all things coming-of-age-angsty-teenager-related (including angsty teenagers who are coming of age), I managed to actually enjoy this. A lot, in fact.</p>

<p>8.99/10, and you get +20 to &ldquo;Ability to understand pop culture references&rdquo;, assuming you&rsquo;re in that skill tree.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen - Argo [2012]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/02/16/vsromophas-argo/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T13:40:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/02/16/vsromophas-argo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Argo is a 2012 American thriller film[3] directed by Ben Affleck; it is a dramatization of and is based on a 2007 article about the &#8220;Canadian Caper&rdquo;,[4] in which Tony Mendez, a CIA operative, led the rescue of six U.S. diplomats from Tehran, Iran, during the 1979 Iran hostage crisis.&ldquo; &ndash; Wikipedia</p>

<p>Intense. Charged. Veeeeery good.</p>

<p>9/10, at least.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen - Bridesmaids [2011]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/12/14/vsromophas-bridesmaids/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T16:35:39-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/12/14/vsromophas-bridesmaids</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Bridesmaids is a 2011 American comedy film written by Kristen Wiig and Annie Mumolo, directed by Paul Feig and produced by Judd Apatow, Barry Mendel, and Clayton Townsend. The plot centers on Annie (Wiig), who suffers a series of misfortunes after being asked to serve as maid of honor for her best friend, Lillian (Maya Rudolph). Rose Byrne, Melissa McCarthy, Ellie Kemper, and Wendi McLendon-Covey costar as Annie&rsquo;s fellow bridesmaids, with Chris O&#8217;Dowd and Jill Clayburgh—who died of leukemia in November 2010 before the film was released—playing key supporting roles.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridesmaids_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bridesmaids_</a>(2011_film)</p>

<p>Immature, cringe-worthy, disgusting and horrifying. You know, exactly what makes every Judd Apatow film worth watching.</p>

<p>Simultaneously 1/10 and 8/10. But mostly 8/10.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
