<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: In | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-14T20:41:07-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Zombieland [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/19/vsromophas-zombieland/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-19T17:18:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/19/vsromophas-zombieland</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Zombieland is an American zombie comedy film directed by Ruben Fleischer from a screenplay written by Rhett Reese and Paul Wernick. The film stars Woody Harrelson, Jesse Eisenberg, Emma Stone, and Abigail Breslin as survivors of a zombie post-apocalypse. Together they take an extended road trip in an attempt to find a sanctuary free from zombies; Columbus (Eisenberg) follows a set of "rules&rdquo; designed to keep them alive where others have failed; Tallahasee (Harrelson) kills zombies in a variety of creative ways while trying to &ldquo;enjoy the little things&rdquo; in a ruined world.&ldquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zombieland">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zombieland</a></p>

<p>Feels like a level out of Left 4 Dead in movie form. Almost as fun, too.</p>

<p>8/10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Role Models [2008]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/08/vsromophas-role-models/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-08T18:37:53-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/07/08/vsromophas-role-models</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Role Models is a 2008 American comedy film directed by David Wain about two energy drink salesmen who are ordered to perform 150 hours of community service as punishment for various offenses. For their service, the two men work at a program designed to pair kids with adult role models. The film stars Seann William Scott, Paul Rudd, Christopher Mintz-Plasse, Bobb'e J. Thompson, Jane Lynch, and Elizabeth Banks.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role_models">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Role_models</a></p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re looking for another dumb movie with cheap laughs, you&rsquo;ve found one.</p>

<p>4/10, mainly due to the redeeming feature that is Jane Lynch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
