<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vsromophas | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/vsromophas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T13:22:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Fantastic Mr. Fox [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2011/01/07/vsromophas-fantastic-mr-fox/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-07T23:07:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2011/01/07/vsromophas-fantastic-mr-fox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Fantastic Mr. Fox is a 2009 stop-motion animated film based on the Roald Dahl children&rsquo;s novel of the same name, released in the autumn of 2009. It was produced by Regency Enterprises and Indian Paintbrush, and features the voices of George Clooney, Meryl Streep, Jason Schwartzman, and Bill Murray. It is the first animated film directed by Wes Anderson, and the first stop-motion animated film to be distributed by 20th Century Fox, also the first film by Anderson not to be rated R by the MPAA. Development on the project began in 2004 as collaboration between Anderson and Henry Selick (who worked with Anderson on the 2004 film The Life Aquatic with Steve Zissou) under Revolution Studios. In 2007 Revolution folded, Selick left to direct Coraline, and work on the film moved to 20th Century Fox. Production began in London in 2007.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Mr._Fox_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fantastic_Mr._Fox_</a>(film)</p>

<p>Somehow, this film&rsquo;s incredible stop-motion animation and quirkiness fully makes up for the fact that the story could have a used a bit more work.</p>

<p>9/10 &ndash; within a margin of error of 0.05%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Fanboys [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2011/01/05/vsromophas-fanboys/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-05T08:06:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2011/01/05/vsromophas-fanboys</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Fanboys is a 2009 comedy film directed by Kyle Newman and starring Sam Huntington, Chris Marquette, Dan Fogler, Jay Baruchel and Kristen Bell. It was released in the United States on February 6, 2009, and in Canada on April 3, 2009.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fanboys_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fanboys_</a>(2009_film)</p>

<p>Not funny to non-fanboys, and so full of dumb stereotypes that it&rsquo;s probably on the verge of offensive towards actual fanboys.</p>

<p>3/10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Full Metal Jacket [1987]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/12/12/vsromophas-full-metal-jacket/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-12T16:48:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/12/12/vsromophas-full-metal-jacket</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Full Metal Jacket is a 1987 war film by Stanley Kubrick, based on the novel The Short-Timers by Gustav Hasford. The title refers to the full metal jacket bullet used by infantry riflemen. The film follows a squad of U.S. Marines through their training and depicts some of the experiences of two of them in the Tet Offensive (1968) during the Vietnam War.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Full_Metal_Jacket">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Full_Metal_Jacket</a></p>

<p>Good. Damned good.</p>

<p>9.6789/10 &ndash; a new top 10 entry for sure</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Animal Crackers [1930]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/12/08/vsromophas-animal-crackers/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-08T08:16:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/12/08/vsromophas-animal-crackers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Animal Crackers is a 1930 American comedy film, in which mayhem and zaniness ensue when a valuable painting goes missing during a party in honor of famed African explorer Captain Spaulding. The film was both a critical and commercial success upon initial release, and remains one of the Marx Brothers' most beloved and often-quoted movies. Filming was done at Kaufman Astoria Studios in Astoria, Queens, and was the last film the brothers would make in New York.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Crackers_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Animal_Crackers_</a>(film)</p>

<p>&ldquo;Captain, this leaves me speechless!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Well, see that you remain that way.&rdquo;</p>

<p>7/10 &ndash; if you&rsquo;re looking for clean, silly wordplay humour, look here. If you aren&rsquo;t, go away.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: The Men Who Stare at Goats [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/11/17/vsromophas-the-men-who-stare-at-goats/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-17T23:53:25-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/11/17/vsromophas-the-men-who-stare-at-goats</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;The Men Who Stare at Goats is a 2009 slapstick comedy war film directed by Grant Heslov and written by Peter Straughan and released in theaters on November 6, 2009. It is based on the book of the same title by author Jon Ronson, an account of the investigation by Ronson and John Sergeant[3] into attempts by US military forces to use psychic powers.&rdquo; - <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Men_Who_Stare_at_Goats_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Men_Who_Stare_at_Goats_</a>(film)</p>

<p>If you liked Burn After Reading, you&rsquo;ll like this. However, if you don&rsquo;t want to wait 80 minutes for an ending scene that you may or may not find hilarious, this does not an entertaining film make.</p>

<p>6.66/10 &ndash; a slapstick comedy war film with only slapstick and war for the most part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
