<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vsromophas | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/vsromophas/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-10T19:27:02-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Behind Enemy Lines [2001]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-behind-enemy-lines/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:04:45-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-behind-enemy-lines</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Based on a fictional US Navy F-18 navigator who gets shot down over a supposedly DMZ during what is supposedly the Bosnian conflict of the early &lsquo;90s.</p>

<p>Good enough storyline, somewhat original. Cheesy special effects (it was almost 10 years ago, you know), and too many clichés. Evil Russian sniper anyone?</p>

<p>5.2445/10, for lack of imagination and trying to make me take Owen Wilson seriously.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 2 February 2010 at 19:42</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Starship Troopers [1997]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-starship-troopers/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:03:48-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-starship-troopers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sci-fi that &ldquo;follows a young soldier named Johnny Rico and his exploits in the Mobile Infantry, a futuristic military unit. Rico&rsquo;s military career progresses from recruit to non-commissioned officer and finally to officer against the backdrop of an interstellar war between mankind and an arachnoid species known as "the Bugs&rdquo;.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starship_Troopers_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Starship_Troopers_</a>(film</p>

<p>Special effects that make some newer films look amateur, this is a surprisingly funny (read: over-the-top and ridiculous) parody of militarism and totalitarianism. Lame storyline and acting, but hey, this is science fiction. Get used to it.</p>

<p>7.56/10</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 3 February 2010 at 19:48</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Fight Club [1999]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-fight-club/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-10T15:02:58-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/10/vsromophas-fight-club</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Fight Club is a 1999 American film adapted from the 1996 novel of the same name by Chuck Palahniuk. The film was directed by David Fincher and stars Edward Norton, Brad Pitt, and Helena Bonham Carter. Norton plays the unnamed protagonist, an "everyman&rdquo; who is discontented with his white-collar job in American society. He forms a &ldquo;fight club&rdquo; with soap salesman Tyler Durden, played by Pitt, and becomes embroiled in a relationship with him and a dissolute woman, Marla Singer, played by Carter.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_Club_">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fight_Club_</a>(film)</p>

<p>An intricate (but not overly confusing) storyline, intense (yet believable) acting, and a kickass soundtrack. Oh, and a sick sense of humour throughout the entire thing. No wonder people love this film. Definitely a new addition to my top ten. Messed up and awesome.</p>

<p>9.9999/10, because nobody is perfect.</p>

<p>(As a not related note, is there a single film Edward Norton is in that ISN&rsquo;T awesome? I mean, seriously&hellip;)</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 4 February 2010 at 20:28</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: (500) Days of Summer [2009]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-500-days-of-summer/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T19:55:43-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-500-days-of-summer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;(500) Days of Summer is a 2009 romantic-drama-comedy film. It was written by Scott Neustadter and Michael H. Weber, directed by Marc Webb, produced by Mark Waters, and stars Joseph Gordon-Levitt and Zooey Deschanel. The story is presented in a nonlinear narrative structure and depicts a memory-driven look at a failed romance.&rdquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/</a>(500)_Days_of_Summer</p>

<p>Not a movie that I would usually like, but I was somehow smiling the whole way through. Then again, that could just be Zooey Deschanel. One of those films that bills itself as &ldquo;quirky&rdquo;, this is one of the few that does it relatively well. Not sure that the comedy tag fits this film &ndash; although amusing, I&rsquo;m not sure that I ever actually laughed. Well, except at the impromptu musical number.</p>

<p>8.5/10 &ndash; would be 7.5, but Zooey Deschanel&rsquo;s cuteness gives an extra point.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 4 February 2010 at 23:58</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Very Short Reviews of Movies Other People Have Already Seen: Top Gun [1986]]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-top-gun/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-09T19:54:11-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/11/09/vsromophas-top-gun</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;This film stars Tom Cruise, Kelly McGillis, Anthony Edwards, Val Kilmer, Meg Ryan, and Tom Skerritt. Cruise plays Lieutenant Pete "Maverick&rdquo; Mitchell, a young Naval aviator on board the aircraft carrier USS Enterprise. He and his Naval Flight Officer (Radar Intercept Officer &ndash; the &ldquo;RIO&rdquo; &ndash; the &ldquo;back seater&rdquo; in the two-man F-14 Tomcat) Lt. j.g. Nick &ldquo;Goose&rdquo; Bradshaw are given the chance to train at the Navy&rsquo;s Fighter Weapons School, after the pilot above him in the squadron rankings resigns from duty following a very stressful mission. This film depicts Maverick&rsquo;s progress through the training, his romance with a female instructor, and his overcoming a crisis of confidence following a fatal training accident.&ldquo; &ndash; <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_gun">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Top_gun</a></p>

<p>No idea why this film was so popular. Maybe it&rsquo;s just the 80s hairstyles, but sitting through the entire length of this film was actually quite excruciating. Not sure if it&rsquo;s action, romance, or just a blatant US Navy recruiting project.</p>

<p><em>Originally posted on Facebook on 5 February 2010 at 20:28</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
