<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Notes | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T16:50:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connecting PC Headset Mic to Mixer (Steinberg CI1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/10/19/connecting-pc-headset-mic-to-mixer-steinberg-ci1/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-19T18:40:52-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/10/19/connecting-pc-headset-mic-to-mixer-steinberg-ci1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is what I would thoroughly classify under, &ldquo;rare, but irksome&rdquo; problems.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got a Steinberg CI1 mixer that I use as an input for my guitar, and have my KRK studio monitors plugged into for output. It&rsquo;s plugged into my computer as well, so I can either run the guitar to the monitors, or my PC&rsquo;s sound (or both). The mixer uses either line-level or +48V phantom power for the inputs. Which is great for a guitar, or for a professional microphone, but the microphones in PC headsets (mostly condenser mics, which are fairly cheap) run at the +5V supplied by a computer&rsquo;s soundcard. Which is&hellip; awkward, and since I just bought a shiny new Razer Blackshark headset, I figured I should find a way to plug the PC mic into the mixer, for convenience and whatnot.</p>

<p>So, I found a way. It takes the mic signal from the 3.5mm TRS connector from the headset, amplifies it, and outputs to a &frac14;" TS connector (although it could just as easily be a 3.5mm TS jack, if that&rsquo;s what you required). Pretty simple, parts list as follows:</p>

<ul>
<li>3.5mm female TRS connector jack</li>
<li>&frac14;" male TS connector (with some cable attached, I just used part of an old guitar cable)</li>
<li>10uF capacitor (I&rsquo;d say 16V+, the one I&rsquo;ve used is 100V, but that&rsquo;s overkill, just what I had)</li>
<li>2.2kOhm resistor</li>
<li>9V battery connector</li>
</ul>


<p>The circuit diagram is as follows:</p>

<p><img src="http://mahler.ca/notablog/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/PC-Headset-to-Mixer-amp.jpg" alt="Circuit diagram for amp" /></p>

<p>That&rsquo;s uhh&hellip; That&rsquo;s pretty much it. I put it into a fancy little project box, to make it fancy, as below. Aside from that, just connect the 9V battery whenever you need to use the mic, plug your headset into the 3.5mm end, then plug the &frac14;" side into the mixer, and you should be good to go!</p>

<p>Fancy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Psychology? That's the (Easiest|hardest) Degree Ever!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/05/26/psychology-thats-the-easiest-hardest-degree-ever/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-26T19:36:14-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2013/05/26/psychology-thats-the-easiest-hardest-degree-ever</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Possible things, then, will be all those things that are not impossible things &ndash; that is, all those things that are either contingent or necessary. If there are no necessary things then all possible things will be contingent and all contingent things will be possible. If there is a necessary thing, however, then there will be a possible thing which is not contingent.&rdquo; &ndash; Philosophy: The Quest For Truth (Pojman, Vaughn)</p>

<p>This is a quote from a textbook for a first year philosophy course.</p>

<p>I have long maintained that the idea that some academic programs are harder than others is preposterous. I&rsquo;ve experienced this from both ends &ndash; people telling me that I &ldquo;must be really smart to be in computer engineering&rdquo;, since there&rsquo;s &ldquo;no way they could do that!&rdquo;, as well as those informing me that psychology is &ldquo;waaaaaay harder&rdquo; than computer engineering, because it requires &ldquo;hours of reading every day, and you&rsquo;ve got to write a thesis and if you don&rsquo;t get published your entire degree is a waste!&rdquo; Both of these statements I find to be a bit&hellip; well, rather silly.</p>

<p>For example: I find the textbook paragraph above extremely difficult to parse and understand, whereas a language-brain-type would have no issue doing so; that said, I am likely able to parse and understand concepts of analog signals better than they would. It&rsquo;s much less a matter of the content, and more a matter of the reader or learner. Different people have difficulty with different things, simple as that.</p>

<p>While anecdotal evidence is a logical fallacy (see <a href="https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/anecdotal">https://yourlogicalfallacyis.com/anecdotal</a>), and I am in no way basing my conclusions off just this, my own progress and marks (most notably in my university career, although a similar analysis could be done for high school if I had the marks accessible) are a good example of how wrong this claim is. Last term &ndash; my second half of 3rd year computer engineering (honours) at the University of Waterloo &ndash; I took Psych 101 as an elective. You know, THE Psych 101 course. The one that seemingly everybody who has ever been to university has taken &ndash; and passed without any effort. Well, I got a lower mark in THE Psych 101 course than I did in my 3rd-year computer networks course, despite Psych 101 being generally recognized as a bird course for first years. In fact, I received a lower mark in Psych 101 than I received in my 3rd-year engineering economics course as well. Speaking of that, I also took Econ 102 (macroeconomics, another one of those everybody-takes-it first year courses) in the same term, and received nearly the same mark in it as the aforementioned 3rd year engineering economics course &ndash; a course that should, by it&rsquo;s description at least, be much more difficult. So what gives?</p>

<p>Now, you might think this breaks down to amount of effort put in. Undoubtedly, I spent more time on my engineering courses than I did my Psych 101 and Econ 102 electives. But, quite frankly, that wasn&rsquo;t the root cause of the lower marks. The entire term, I knew that it wasn&rsquo;t time, or studying that would enable me to get 100% in these supposedly simple, throwaway courses. I knew what would, though &ndash; nothing. Well, nothing short of a brain transplant. Thing is, I don&rsquo;t have the brain required for social sciences, or economics, or (apparently) philosophy. These are topics that require huge amounts of memorization, which I am simply unable to do (unless you&rsquo;re talking Arrested Development quotes, that&rsquo;s an exception). They also are topics where there is, at times, very little connectedness &ndash; although this may only be from my perspective, really. I find the topics we learn about in our computer engineering courses to be very interrelated, both within topics in a course as well as within courses (even spanning multiple years), whereas I don&rsquo;t see this same sort of network forming with other subjects. Adding to my perhaps skewed perception is the professors teaching these courses. My engineering economics course and Econ 102 had similar content, but the engineering one was framed in such a way that it had more of that connectedness, and I was therefore able to do just fine in it. On the other hand, Econ 102 was presented more as a loosely-connected list of concepts, without much &ldquo;glue&rdquo; tying them together in real-world application, making it much harder for me to really understand what was going on.</p>

<p>So, am I insane? Or do I have a point here? I don&rsquo;t actually know to be honest. Thing is, at this point, having been through most of a university degree, there&rsquo;s really no way for me to compare. If I were to pursue a degree in psychology after graduating, it would be an unfair comparison. I already have experience with the university education system, allowing me to effectively game the system at times, much like students do in high school. (Other students, I mean. Not me. I was a workaholic for those four years. Totally.)</p>

<p>In conclusion (he wrote, feeling a bit like a high school student trapped in an essay), it seems to me that while not all degrees are created equal, not all people are created equal either, and we therefore cannot judge the relative merit of degrees based on perceived difficulty. The grass is always greener on the other side of the fence, so we tend to take pity on ourselves and think that we&rsquo;re in the roughest spot, and that everybody else has it easy. Well guess what? They don&rsquo;t. Stop saying they do. Putting them down to make yourself feel better kinda makes you a jerk, and if there&rsquo;s one thing I know, there isn&rsquo;t a course that is designed for the jerk-brained.</p>

<p>(In preparation for philosophy essay due next week, I am adding a few sentences down here to bring the word count up to 1000 words. It&rsquo;s amazing that I can just braindump this much without even trying, whereas said philosophy essay is taking far, far more effort. Shoot, 989 at that last sentence. So, now I&rsquo;m at 1000. Exactly, actually.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winter Tires vs. Snow Tires - Who Gives a Damn? (I Do, and You Should Too.)]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/12/11/winter-tires-vs-snow-tires/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T04:49:05-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/12/11/winter-tires-vs-snow-tires</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Okay folks, it&rsquo;s time for me to let you in on a little secret, one that I&rsquo;ve learned from living in the north for most of my life &ndash; &ldquo;snow tires&rdquo; and &ldquo;winter tires&rdquo; are NOT the same thing, and confusing the two is, to put it lightly, not a great idea.</p>

<p>Snow tires are barely available anymore &ndash; see <a href="http://www.wheels.ca/how-do-winter-tires-differ-from-snow-tires/%C2%A0for">http://www.wheels.ca/how-do-winter-tires-differ-from-snow-tires/%C2%A0for</a> more information &ndash; and are meant for deep snow driving. The equivalent of a deep-paddle snowmobile track. Know what they&rsquo;re terrible for? Pavement. While surface area doesn&rsquo;t increase friction (actually reduces it), it&rsquo;s important to have a larger contact patch on slippery surfaces, so that there is a greater chance of some part of the contact patch grips.</p>

<p>Alright, so who gives a damn? They don&rsquo;t make snow tires anymore, why bother with the distinction? Well, it seems that people are stuck on the term &ldquo;snow tires&rdquo;, and therefore think that they should only remove their &ldquo;all&rdquo;-season tires when the snow flies. (&ldquo;All-season&rdquo; is not a name that makes sense here &ndash; not for shoes, and not for tires.) This is, quite simply, wrong. Want to know when you should remove the all-seasons? When it&rsquo;s below 7 degrees. Yep. Seven degrees Celsius. Above zero. (see <a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/globe-drive/car-tips/why-you-still-need-winter-tires-on-dry-pavement/article4180768/,">http://www.theglobeandmail.com/globe-drive/car-tips/why-you-still-need-winter-tires-on-dry-pavement/article4180768/,</a> <a href="http://www.guideautoweb.com/en/articles/3701/,">http://www.guideautoweb.com/en/articles/3701/,</a> and <a href="http://www.wheels.ca/why-winter-tires-there-are-many-reasons/">http://www.wheels.ca/why-winter-tires-there-are-many-reasons/</a>) This is because the composition of all-season tires and winter tires is very different. When it goes below 7, the ability of all-seasons to flex is drastically reduced, meaning they can&rsquo;t properly grip pavement. Winter tires, on the other hand, are made of softer compounds, and so are more able to do so. This makes an immense difference, one that only 37% of Canadians are aware of. (Apparently, <a href="http://www.winnipegfreepress.com/local/manitobans-dont-roll-on-winter-tires-181961121.html">only 37% of Canadians own winter tires</a>.) As someone who has driven with and without winter tires on snow, I can confirm that the difference is rather noticeable.</p>

<p>Oh, and for the record &ndash; the last time it was consistently above 7 degrees in Waterloo was October 27th. So, 6 weeks ago is when everybody should have switched to the winter tires, and yet most cars I see are still rocking the crappy all-seasons.</p>

<p>I will state that I personally don&rsquo;t own a car, and so I wouldn&rsquo;t have to buy them. Yes, they are expensive. But consider that since you&rsquo;re switching to your winter tires for 4 months of the year, your all-seasons will last 33% longer, and not running into poles or other cars is always a good way to save money, too!</p>

<p>So please, for your safety, for the safety of other drivers, and for the safety of utility poles all over &ndash; get some <em>winter</em> tires, and use them!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philosophy of Life - the Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/06/08/philosophy-of-life-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T17:35:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/06/08/philosophy-of-life-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This was written as an assignment for my grade 12 religion class, which I recently re-discovered. Interesting for me to read, to see how it aligns with that which I believe now, but likely boring as hell for others. Enjoy at your own risk.</em></p>

<p>Some people live for the present, others in the past. I prefer to live for the future. This is because I believe that the future holds huge amount of promise, both for humanity and for myself. In fact, I often cannot wait to see what amazing things will happen in the future.</p>

<p>Interestingly, I do not believe that someday in the future, all of the world&rsquo;s problems will be solved. However, my outlook is nonetheless rather positive. Technological and medical advancements, along with more widespread education, are slowly but surely raising the standard of living throughout the world. Sometimes it may not seem this way, with millions dying every year of starvation, but if we look back in history, there is definitely an upward trend in people&rsquo;s happiness with their lives. For example, every time a new cure is found and put into practice, hundreds, thousands, maybe even millions of lives are saved. However, we must remember that these things can take time, and the one thing that the future has plenty of, is time.</p>

<p>Another aspect regarding the future that people have a philosophy about is whether or not to plan for it. Some people choose to organize every moment of their lives, from dawn until dusk. Others never plan a thing, and prefer to live on the wild side. I find myself on both ends of the spectrum, depending on what it is we are talking about. For example, I think it is important to plan education. As I apply to universities for next year, I realize how important it is to stay organized, and plan ahead so that I do not miss deadlines. Conversely, there are things that I prefer to be somewhat unorganized. In the summer of 2006, my family went on a canoeing trip in Quetico Park, in Ontario. Although we knew where we going, and approximately when, most of the trip was largely unplanned. In the end, it ended up being one of the most exciting vacations I have ever been on. Living without planning, along with the fact that we were somewhat “in the wild” added a sort of excitement to the whole thing, that people who meticulously plan every detail will unfortunately never experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philosophy of Life - Happiness]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/06/04/philosophy-of-life-happiness/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-04T13:40:59-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2012/06/04/philosophy-of-life-happiness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This was written as an assignment for my grade 12 religion class, which I recently re-discovered. Interesting for me to read, to see how it aligns with that which I believe now, but likely boring as hell for others. Enjoy at your own risk.</em></p>

<p>Nobody can honestly say that they do not want to be happy in their lives. Some will claim otherwise, but this is generally just a call for attention. Because this is the case, it seems only fitting to have a section on what some see as the goal of life, happiness, in my philosophy of life.</p>

<p>I will start by answering the simplest question about happiness, yet possibly the most difficult to answer: what is happiness? This is a very important question to ask, as it is the answer to this that can very well decide whether an individual will ever be truly happy with their lives. For some, happiness is not easily attained. Instead, it requires a very specific set of circumstances – perhaps a family, perhaps money, perhaps love – before they can be happy. For others, like myself, happiness comes more from the simple fact that I know that I am alive and well. Maybe this seems quaint and cliche, but it is the honest truth. Because I do not believe in the afterlife, what I do in this life is very important, and because of this, what I do in this life makes me happy. According to some studies, involvement in a religion actually tends to make people happier. I personally feel that although this is possible, it may have something to do with their beliefs. If someone is not happy, perhaps they see this is a sign that they are unhappy with what their god has given them in life, which would be considered blasphemous.</p>

<p>It is difficult to describe the situation in which I would be most happy. I am fairly certain that I would not be rich and famous, not be around computers, nor would I be on an island in the middle of nowhere, alone with my thoughts. I think that because I am so happy with my day to day life, it is actually very hard to describe a happier situation. On the other hand, perhaps I am afraid that if I do think of a happier place, I will spend all my time dreaming about it, and get nothing done until I find myself in that place!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
