<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Notes | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-14T19:26:22-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary of a Polyphasic Sleeper, Part I - Der Anfang]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T23:59:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this note is written for nobody in particular. More just a reference.</p>

<p>As several people are aware, I have been sleeping polyphasically recently. For those unaware of the meaning of polyphasic, it simply means that you sleep in installments throughout the day, as opposed to once per 24-hour cycle. For example, there is a polyphasic sleep schedule called the &ldquo;Uberman&rdquo; schedule, wherein the individual takes six 20-minute naps in a 24-hour period. Yup, two hours of sleep every 24 hours. I am not an &ldquo;Uber man&rdquo;, though, so I opted for a simpler one.</p>

<p>Basically, I wake up about the same time every morning, about 7:30. Yes, even weekends, and that is key. My classes end around 12:00 usually, so I come home for lunch, and take a half-hour nap (usually 12:30-1:00). I go to afternoon classes, which go to 4:30, come home, and take another half-hour nap from 5:00-5:30 or so. Finally, I sleep again from about 10:30-11:00.</p>

<p>These three half-hour naps are complemented by a big 3 to 5 hour sleep ending at around 7:30am. The length of this nap is variable, and depends on how tired I am any particular day. For example, I sometimes miss a nap in the day for one reason or another. If this is the case, I usually end up being tired at around 2am, and so go to sleep at this point. If I had three excellent naps during the day (as I did today), I&rsquo;ll stay awake until 4 or so. No matter how awake I am, though, this big sleep needs to be at least 3 hours.</p>

<p>To be able to do this, you basically have to trick yourself into going into REM sleep almost instantly, eliminating all the tossing and turning that most people don&rsquo;t realize they do. Meditation helps, looking at the clock worrying that you won&rsquo;t get to sleep does not. I&rsquo;ve only been doing this for a week, and I&rsquo;m already getting into the swing of it. Not only do I fall asleep within a few minutes, but my body and mind are starting to feel tired right around whenever I usually take naps (this is why I don&rsquo;t like skipping naps). I return to my point of waking up at 7:30 on weekends, which is because if you get out of schedule, you may have problems getting back into it.</p>

<p>Some people (my mother) have expressed concerns that this is not healthy. Although I am fairly certain that doing this for extended periods of time would have adverse effects, I will only be doing this until December, and do not believe that it will cause problems. My only complaint is that my legs occasionally hurt due to lack of rest, but this is a problem I have always had, and most people will probably not experience this.</p>

<p>The advantages of this sleep schedule are very apparent, and quite worth it so far. I have about 3 or 4 more hours of being awake every day, which is great. However, the biggest change I have noticed is that when I am awake, I am truly awake. I can work on programming assignments at 2:30 in the morning, and realize the next morning that I actually did them right. This, to me, is the greatest advantage. When sleeping monophasically (one big sleep every night), I would come home after lectures and be exhausted. After sitting around for a couple hours, I could get 2, maybe 3 hours of solid work done in the evening. But after this, I was again too tired to continue. Not anymore. I get about 6 to 8 hours of solid working time per day now, which is great. I can do groceries at 2am (yay 24h Sobey&rsquo;s!) and not mistake Head and Shoulders for crackers. For the first time since arriving at Waterloo, I am almost on time with my assignments!</p>

<p>Hard sleep, hard&hellip; awakedness? I guess that&rsquo;s what this comes down to. Once you&rsquo;re into it, you sleep deeply, even during naps, and you are very awake when you are awake.</p>

<p>3:13am, and I can still type this. See how this works?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary of a Polyphasic Sleeper, Part II - Der Untergang/Das Ende]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T18:03:37-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Originally published December 5th, 2009)</p>

<p>Follow-up to the previous note about polyphasic sleeping. I have now finished my experiment in polyphasic sleep, and am ready to make some conclusions.</p>

<p>As a recap, my schedule consisted of sleeping about 4 hours a night, with 3 half-hour naps during the day (noon, 5pm and 10pm). I did this for six weeks, with few exceptions. I stayed as close to this schedule as possible, only missing maybe 1 out of every 10 or 15 naps (not bad considering how random and hectic life can be).</p>

<p>One weekend, I did not have any naps, as I spent it in Guelph. Fortunately, I had a good sleep on the Saturday night. However, I was still wrecked for several days afterwards. Even though at that point I had only been doing this for two weeks or so, I was already dependent on my naps &ndash; a testament to the creature of habit that humans really are. Aside from this, I would once in a while miss a nap (usually my 5pm one), which made me a bit tired in the evening, but this was generally remedied by having a slightly longer nap at 10pm.</p>

<p>I also have noted that I became quite good at training myself to wake up without an alarm. Although I always set one as a backup, during my half-hour naps I would generally wake up one or two minutes before it went off. This was not the case in the morning after sleeping 4 hours, though.</p>

<h3>Der Untergang</h3>

<p>In the last week, since exams are coming up, and assignments are no longer a concern, I decided that I would stop the polyphasic sleep. However, being as I am, I decided to do a quick few experiments before I stopped. One of these includes skipping my first two naps. This was, quite simply, disastrous. I was extremely tired in the afternoon and evening, and my 10pm nap ended up being three hours (meaning I was sleeping for two hours while my clock radio was playing before I woke up &ndash; that&rsquo;s how tired I was).</p>

<p>Not really important, but somewhat amusing is that (as I mentioned above) I became so used to sleeping in half-hour chunks that last Saturday I woke up at 8:15am (about normal), but decided to try to sleep in. However, after falling back asleep, I awoke again at 8:45. Tried again, woke up at 9:15. Decided that my body would win this time, got out of bed, and started my day.</p>

<p>Today is going to be my first day that I am not going to take a nap in nearly a month. I am quite tired right now, even though it is not even six o'clock and I woke up at 10 this morning. Unfortunately, this means that I will not have a very effective evening of studying, as I am finding it extremely hard to focus. Hopefully after a good night&rsquo;s sleep tonight, tomorrow will be more conducive towards studying.</p>

<h3>Das Ende</h3>

<p>Being the scientific (well, Engineering) mind that I am, I did this not only as a way to increase available time, but as a sort of experiment. Some conclusions:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>This did not make me any more difficult to understand/any less coherent. Usually when someone is exhausted, they tend to make less sense. However, I did not receive any comments from people around me that seemed to indicate that this was the case. To me, this indicates that I was probably as confusing as ever, but not in way that indicated exhaustion.</p></li>
<li><p>A big part of the &ldquo;available time&rdquo; part for me was time for assignments and schoolwork. Although I did not notice an increase in my marks in assignments and quizzes since doing this, they certainly did not drop. As is normal with any course, the later material tends to be more difficult to grasp, and my marks generally show this. However, they did not go down by any notable amount. Because I had so much time, I was able to do many of the suggested questions on assignments, read the textbook, and just generally have a better idea of what was going on in my courses.</p></li>
<li><p>As a final note, I had a lot more time to do stuff I wanted to do. In the first half of the term, I was extremely concerned that I would not have enough time to just finish assignments, so I went to few social events, and very little time for anything other than work. Since then, however, I have been to all sorts of EngSoc events, social events, extracurricular stuff, as well as having lots of time to watch movies. LOTS of movies. One might say that thanks to polyphasic sleep, I am far more cultured that I was two months ago, having watched many classic films when I would generally have been sleeping.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>If there are mistakes in here, this is most likely because, for the first time six weeks, I am tired. Must&hellip; resist&hellip; urge to nap. Maybe I&rsquo;ll go for groceries, and not at 1:30am this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
