<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Notes | Ryan Mahler]]></title>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/categories/notes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ryantmer.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-15T13:19:25-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://ryantmer.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Ryan Mahler]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[There Is No Such Thing as Free Time...]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/11/01/there-is-no-such-thing-as-free-time/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-01T08:10:20-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/11/01/there-is-no-such-thing-as-free-time</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&hellip; So please stop saying it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[100 Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/10/14/100-things/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-14T18:13:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/10/14/100-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since everyone likes to think they&rsquo;re so deep with the crap they put on Facebook, I decided to give it a shot. I decided to write 100 things about myself. Surprisingly hard.</p>

<p>I am me.
I am not short, but there are many taller than I am.
I am a skinny white kid.
I am darker than most people think, but not in the way that most people think.
I am myopic.
I am not shortsighted.
I have good night vision.
I am sometimes completely blind.
I don&rsquo;t not shave because I&rsquo;m going for a “look”.
I don&rsquo;t shave because I&rsquo;m lazy.
I genuinely do not care about my appearance.
I do care about how I feel about myself.
I do care about how others feel about me.
I can&rsquo;t touch my nose with my tongue.
I wear what I want.
I don&rsquo;t wear what you wear.
I don&rsquo;t wear what you don&rsquo;t wear.
I make my own decisions.
I don&rsquo;t make decisions based on commercials and media.
I don&rsquo;t make decisions based against commercials and media.
I judge music based on it&rsquo;s own merits.
I don&rsquo;t like “that new band”.
I don&rsquo;t like “that new band” because everybody else likes it.
I don&rsquo;t not like “that new band” because everybody else likes it.
I walk my own path in life.
I won&rsquo;t go where everyone else is going.
I won&rsquo;t not go where everyone else is going because everyone else is going there.
I enjoy possessions more than money.
I know what having feels like.
I know what loss feels like.
I have some thoughts which are beyond comprehension outside my head.
I can&rsquo;t express my thoughts in words.
I am simple.
I seek happiness.
I like a good time.
I like good fun and bad fun.
I mean it when I say I&rsquo;m not thinking about anything.
I have no rhyme nor reason – I do something because I want to.
I like to think up elaborate stories in my head, but I never write them down.
I am selfish, just like everyone else.
I am complex, just like everyone else.
I can&rsquo;t see myself in 20 years.
I can&rsquo;t see myself in 5 years.
I can&rsquo;t see myself tomorrow.
I don&rsquo;t write poetry.
I write thoughts.
I don&rsquo;t quote song lyrics to appear “deep” or “thoughtful”.
I quote song lyrics because I want to.
I don&rsquo;t seek revenge.
I don&rsquo;t get angry.
I don&rsquo;t find pleasure in pain.
I don&rsquo;t find pleasure in the pain of others.
I am happy when others are happy, and satisfied when others are satisfied.
I lie to help others.
I don&rsquo;t hate those who hate me.
I don&rsquo;t hate those who love me.
I don&rsquo;t hate those who don&rsquo;t love me back.
I don&rsquo;t hate.
I love the military and military technology.
I don&rsquo;t love war.
I support our troops, but not those who misled them.
I am rational.
I dislike irrational people.
I think Ann Coulter is the most despicable person on the planet.
I think people who ignore or deny climate change are as intelligent as a potato.
I don&rsquo;t think the free market should be allowed to rule the world.
I think people should stop to think about what they think once in a while.
I appreciate what religion has done for us historically.
I think the time for religion has passed.
I appreciate the finer things.
I appreciate the finer things, but not just because everyone else thinks they do too.
I like music.
I like a wide variety of music.
I like loud music.
I dislike autotuned crap.
I like good cheese.
I think bacon should be a food group.
I like technology that makes our lives better.
I am irritated by people who misuse technology.
I am irritated by people who actively disrupt the evolution of technology.
I am irritated by people who actively disrupt the evolution of our species.
I hope for a better future for everybody.
I hope the past was not the best thing that ever happened to everybody.
I don&rsquo;t live in the past.
I don&rsquo;t live in the future.
I live in the present.
I learned to understand when I was very young.
I will understand to learn until I am old.
I sometimes say things I don&rsquo;t mean to.
I sometimes don&rsquo;t say things I mean to.
I sometimes speak without talking.
I sometimes talk without speaking.
I am not as crazy as you think I am.
I am far weirder than you think I am.
I am different than you in every way.
I am better than you in every way.
I am the same as you in every way.
I am worse than you in every way.
I am me.
Deal with it, motherfucker.</p>

<p>I decided that ending with &ldquo;Deal with it&rdquo; sounded incredibly emo/depressed/scene/whateverthefuck/{they&rsquo;re all the same anyway}, so I added profanity to lighten the mood.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie Stubs]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/13/movie-stubs/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-13T15:34:11-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/13/movie-stubs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Found a bunch of movie stubs in a drawer in my room. For no reason other than boredom and too much free time, they are (listed by year):</p>

<p><strong>2003:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Elf</li>
<li>Lord of the Rings: Return of the King</li>
<li>The Cat in the Hat</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2004:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Harry Potter and the Prizoner of Azkaban</li>
<li>Garfield</li>
<li>Shrek 2</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2005:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>None&hellip;?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2006:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Babel</li>
<li>The Holiday</li>
<li>The Pink Panther</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2007:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Transformers</li>
<li>Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix</li>
<li>Blood Diamond</li>
<li>The Golden Compass</li>
<li>Beowulf</li>
<li>Children of Men</li>
<li>Transformers (only movie I have ever seen twice in theaters, afaik)</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2008:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Burn After Reading</li>
<li>The X Files: I Want to Believe</li>
<li>Hancock</li>
<li>Eagle Eye</li>
<li>Juno</li>
<li>The Dark Knight</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>2009:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Transformers 2</li>
<li>Valkyrie</li>
<li>District 9</li>
<li>Watchmen</li>
</ul>


<p>Yep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Diary of a Polyphasic Sleeper, Part I - Der Anfang]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T23:59:13-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/diary-of-a-polyphasic-sleeper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, this note is written for nobody in particular. More just a reference.</p>

<p>As several people are aware, I have been sleeping polyphasically recently. For those unaware of the meaning of polyphasic, it simply means that you sleep in installments throughout the day, as opposed to once per 24-hour cycle. For example, there is a polyphasic sleep schedule called the &ldquo;Uberman&rdquo; schedule, wherein the individual takes six 20-minute naps in a 24-hour period. Yup, two hours of sleep every 24 hours. I am not an &ldquo;Uber man&rdquo;, though, so I opted for a simpler one.</p>

<p>Basically, I wake up about the same time every morning, about 7:30. Yes, even weekends, and that is key. My classes end around 12:00 usually, so I come home for lunch, and take a half-hour nap (usually 12:30-1:00). I go to afternoon classes, which go to 4:30, come home, and take another half-hour nap from 5:00-5:30 or so. Finally, I sleep again from about 10:30-11:00.</p>

<p>These three half-hour naps are complemented by a big 3 to 5 hour sleep ending at around 7:30am. The length of this nap is variable, and depends on how tired I am any particular day. For example, I sometimes miss a nap in the day for one reason or another. If this is the case, I usually end up being tired at around 2am, and so go to sleep at this point. If I had three excellent naps during the day (as I did today), I&rsquo;ll stay awake until 4 or so. No matter how awake I am, though, this big sleep needs to be at least 3 hours.</p>

<p>To be able to do this, you basically have to trick yourself into going into REM sleep almost instantly, eliminating all the tossing and turning that most people don&rsquo;t realize they do. Meditation helps, looking at the clock worrying that you won&rsquo;t get to sleep does not. I&rsquo;ve only been doing this for a week, and I&rsquo;m already getting into the swing of it. Not only do I fall asleep within a few minutes, but my body and mind are starting to feel tired right around whenever I usually take naps (this is why I don&rsquo;t like skipping naps). I return to my point of waking up at 7:30 on weekends, which is because if you get out of schedule, you may have problems getting back into it.</p>

<p>Some people (my mother) have expressed concerns that this is not healthy. Although I am fairly certain that doing this for extended periods of time would have adverse effects, I will only be doing this until December, and do not believe that it will cause problems. My only complaint is that my legs occasionally hurt due to lack of rest, but this is a problem I have always had, and most people will probably not experience this.</p>

<p>The advantages of this sleep schedule are very apparent, and quite worth it so far. I have about 3 or 4 more hours of being awake every day, which is great. However, the biggest change I have noticed is that when I am awake, I am truly awake. I can work on programming assignments at 2:30 in the morning, and realize the next morning that I actually did them right. This, to me, is the greatest advantage. When sleeping monophasically (one big sleep every night), I would come home after lectures and be exhausted. After sitting around for a couple hours, I could get 2, maybe 3 hours of solid work done in the evening. But after this, I was again too tired to continue. Not anymore. I get about 6 to 8 hours of solid working time per day now, which is great. I can do groceries at 2am (yay 24h Sobey&rsquo;s!) and not mistake Head and Shoulders for crackers. For the first time since arriving at Waterloo, I am almost on time with my assignments!</p>

<p>Hard sleep, hard&hellip; awakedness? I guess that&rsquo;s what this comes down to. Once you&rsquo;re into it, you sleep deeply, even during naps, and you are very awake when you are awake.</p>

<p>3:13am, and I can still type this. See how this works?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best of Interwebz]]></title>
    <link href="http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/best-of-interwebz/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-01T18:11:36-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://ryantmer.com/blog/2010/04/01/best-of-interwebz</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>(Originally published March 13th, 2009)</p>

<p>Stuff I randomly found, through stumble or otherwise. None are videos, some link directly to images, though. Safe for work! Except for the stuff that is not safe for work.</p>

<h3>Humour (may be NSFW):</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://safenow.org/">Safety stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.onelinerz.net/top-100-funny-one-liners/">One-liners</a>
<a href="" title="http://villageofjoy.com/25-motivational-posters/">Motivationals</a>
<a href="" title="http://static.funnyjunk.com/pictures/hipocrit0.jpg">Hypocrisy, thy name is the USA.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.bouldertherapist.com/html/humor/WordPlays/lexophiles.htm">Lexophiles.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.sloshspot.com/blog/08-18-2009/Demetri-Martin-Motivational-Posters-201">Demitri Martin stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.allowe.com/Humor/book/When%20Insults%20Had%20Class.htm">Classy insults</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wegame.com/view/Left4Dead_Playground_Style/sizes/">L4D playground</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.cs.northwestern.edu/~riesbeck/mathphyseng.html">Math/Phys/Eng jokes</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wilk4.com/humor/humorm125.htm">Rodney Dangerfield</a>
<a href="" title="http://venganza.org/jellyfish.html">Jellyfish basically suck.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.zoitz.com/comics/coffee3.png">LOL IT&rsquo;S TRUE</a> (ohsnap.)
<a href="" title="http://www.allowe.com/Humor/computerenhancers.htm">&ldquo;computer enhancers&rdquo;</a></p>

<h3>Photography:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://content1.docstoc.com/flash/National%20Geographic%20Pictures.swf">Ooh, pretty.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.petapixel.com/2009/07/10/7-steps-to-taking-clone-photographs/">Clones, you say?</a>
<a href="" title="http://haha.nu/creative/creative-photos-by-chema-madoz/">Creative &lsquo;n stuff.</a>
<a href="" title="http://gigapica.geenstijl.nl/2009/05/mooi_milieu.html">More pictures</a>
<a href="" title="http://sergeydolya.livejournal.com/">Moskva?</a> (In Russian, but the links below most pictures lead to more pictures. Good pictures. And possibly porn, I haven&rsquo;t checked all the links.)</p>

<h3>Inspirational/BAWWWWW:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://www.catsprn.com/rich-poor.htm">Rich/poor</a>
<a href="" title="http://static.funnyjunk.com/pictures/hipocrit0.jpg">And again.</a> (it&rsquo;s both funny and inspirational, stfu)
<a href="" title="http://imgfave.com/image_cache/124146953043433.jpeg">D'AWWWWW</a>
<a href="" title="http://rescomp.stanford.edu/~cheshire/EinsteinQuotes.html">Einstein quotes</a></p>

<h3>Howto/Self-improvement</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://www.petapixel.com/2009/07/10/7-steps-to-taking-clone-photographs/">More clones?</a> (again, it&rsquo;s both)
<a href="" title="http://media.npr.org/programs/atc/features/2008/may/foldingchart540.jpg">How to fold things.</a>
<a href="" title="http://thenonconsumeradvocate.com/exceptions-to-katys-compact-buy-nothing-new/">How to not buy things.</a>
<a href="" title="http://mnmlist.com/">How to not anything.</a>
<a href="" title="http://filesharefreak.com/tutorials/how-to-speed-up-torrents-with-low-seeders/">Torrent stuff</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.wikihow.com/Make-a-Simple-Beverage-Can-Stove">Beverage can stove, you say?</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.mindcafe.org/9-brain-habits-you-did-not-realize-you-had">Brain habits</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.seql.org/100ways.cfm">100 ways to save the earth (oblig. Al Gore)</a></p>

<h3>Stuff that is interesting for reasons other than above:</h3>

<p><a href="" title="http://blogs.denverpost.com/captured/2009/09/10/ian-fisher-american-soldier/">Who is fighting the US&rsquo;s war, you ask? This guy!</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.jlc.net/~useless/telsongs.html">Telephone songs</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.worldwithoutus.com/did_you_know.html">Tha future</a> (dunno about anybody else, but makes me feel insignificant&hellip;)
<a href="" title="http://www.prefixmag.com/news/seven-crimes-that-will-get-you-a-smaller-fine-than/32033/">Murder is not all that bad after all.</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.toptenz.net/top-10-historical-travel-destinations.php">Travel destinations!</a>
<a href="" title="http://www.nikon.com/about/feelnikon/universcale/index_f.htm">Sizes of things, in comparison to other things.</a> (WARNING: Heavy flash and sound, so turn those speakers off if you&rsquo;re at work!)
<a href="" title="http://content.ytmnd.com/content/a/0/8/a0812774c98903448246c7e213bc1fea.gif">Moar future.</a></p>

<p>These are in no particular order. Browse at thy will.</p>

<p>And for good measure, one YouTube video with arguably the best Rube Goldberg machine ever: <a href="" title="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qybUFnY7Y8w">OK Go &ndash; This Too Shall Pass</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
